<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Wordsmiths</title>
    <description>Blog and Content Production Company
</description>
    <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://thewordsmiths.xyz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:16:08 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 00:16:08 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where the heck did they go!?</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Where the heck did they go!?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Fiction,5 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Shoot!&amp;rdquo;, I curse under my breath, as I saw the other &amp;ldquo;ear&amp;rdquo; of my earphones rendered useless, marmalized by my own carelessness, I realise, seeing the tangled mess in my hands. Now, I had no shit to do except stare at the blank, defeated, excited, but again, tired, relieved too faces of my fellow metro riders. I saw a little girl trying to push a man&amp;rsquo;s bag away to get a seat on the floor. Guilt-ridden, I offered her mine, sitting down back again as I saw her shaking her head, a NO. &amp;ldquo;He gave me these super-comfy heels man, just so that I don&amp;rsquo;t feel short! I love him!&amp;rdquo;, chirped a girl two maybe three years younger to me, distracting me from the little girl. I think it&amp;rsquo;s just so that he doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel you&amp;rsquo;re short, my sarcastic subconscious spoke in my head, making me laugh inwardly. Nevertheless, I glanced at her heels, and they told me a different story altogether. Shoe Bites, boils on the front and cuts on ankle, &amp;ldquo;Leave the shoes bro, leave the freak show you&amp;rsquo;re going out with! Go out with me?&amp;rdquo;. Damn! the subconscious was on fire, I cognized, looking at the pretty girl with round eyes that could melt you from within but- Ok, stop right there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, a wave of nostalgia hit me and a faint memory of Ma cleaning my shoes came to my head. &amp;ldquo;Do not say that shoes are not important just because they are on your feet. Keep them prim and proper, it&amp;rsquo;s the shoes that tell the reality in this caked world.&amp;rdquo; Oh well, bang on yet again woman, I miss you. The lovestruck girl&amp;rsquo;s friend seemed clearly irritated with her friend&amp;rsquo;s obsession for her boyfriend. I looked down at her feet, white shoes that looked highly comfortable but were in a mess so deep only freckles of white were visible on them. Her careless attire of slovenly tucked shirt and jeans was true to her footwear, I deduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My quest ensued, I went from gladiators to slip-ons till leather brogues and again, I stopped on a pair of feet to broad to belong to a woman, but the footwear was definitely of a woman, since those were easily the most expensive pair of heels in the whole bogey. I shot a glance right up to the wearer&amp;rsquo;s face, who instantly noticed it. It was a boy, alright, who got truly uncomfortable because of my impolite staring. I tried to manage a smile but it did no good as my eyes betrayed me and I stole a glance again. Now, he caught me. And I started looking at my lap, shifting uncomfortably in my seat when a clear, beautiful voice said, &amp;ldquo;Go on, ask me. I know you want to.&amp;rdquo; I looked up, it was the same guy but the voice? Balderdash escaped my throat, nothing else. &amp;ldquo;They are Dior, I was checking you out before, seeing everyone&amp;rsquo;s feet, judging their lives, it is something I do too. But that&amp;#39;s not what you wanted to know mmh? I am a girl, geez, &amp;nbsp;look at me closely, I am too cute to be a guy&amp;rdquo;, she winked at me. And I surmised that except her sorry haircut and almost flat chest and unisex clothing, she indeed was a girl. I murmured an apology and she got down the next stop, and I mused, smiling, that Ma was truly right, even a person&amp;#39;s clothing befuddled me about their sex, only the footwear was true. Jeez.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my footwear? Simple rubber slippers under a proper kurta and jeans was highly inappropriate and axiomatically suggested my laziness as I was already late for my first class and on cue, I looked down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They. Were. Not. F&amp;rsquo;ing, There.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brain went into a whirlwind as i looked down at my bare feet wondering painfully where I kept my new Nike slippers and I started looking around my seat frantically. The gates were closing at the station, ready for departure. As I looked out the window, silently cursing under my breath, looking at the slow moving platform, I saw the little girl, the girl I offered the seat to a while back, smiling at me, holding the feet shaped form of my black and neon green slippers, waving with her other hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Damn, so that&amp;rsquo;s where they went, I exclaimed, wondering about other idle souls scanning through people&amp;rsquo;s feet and I mused about their conjectures of a man in kurta and no footwear,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple lunatic, a phony philosopher or just a man who lost his shoes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Shubhi Shrivastav&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artwork by- Wang Niandong&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/fiction/2016/10/13/where-the-heck-did-they-go!%3F.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/fiction/2016/10/13/where-the-heck-did-they-go!%3F.html</guid>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shh come here</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Shh come here!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Fiction,3 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could hear the sound of the burning wood, breaking the silence where I stood. Even the crickets were awfully quiet, and the trees refused to sway like they used to before. I was thinking about someone I met the day before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our eyes met in the intense cacophony of the bustling bus. She stood there, a few feet away from me, grabbing on to the hand rest above her, dictating something to an old woman seated below. It seemed like a list that went something like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Cucumber, 3 kilos&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Radish, half-a&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Potatoes, 6 kilos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ceased to listen after that. Frankly, I didn&amp;rsquo;t care about what she said, I was too mesmerized by her voice. The sweet melody made me a bit numb, I felt like I was a ragdoll, resting on a pole, about to fall at any moment. I swear if her voice turned stern right then, my insides would burn, because I felt like a Voodoo Child and she, A black magic woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the thing is, I doubt she noticed our eyes were fixated on each other. I was tempted to just say that &amp;ldquo;She&amp;rsquo;s SO nice!&amp;rdquo;, because that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what my mind was shouting at the top of it&amp;rsquo;s voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she became aware that our eyes were locked together, she looked away promptly. I could feel that she felt uneasy. A few pot-holes and a head bump later, I found myself apologizing to her, my face having an eerily wide smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, she didn&amp;#39;t seem to notice that, but then her eyes held a tinge of grey in them. That didn&amp;#39;t seem to diminish her beauty. We were both busy, talking about everything. I told her that I wasn&amp;#39;t from the city and she told me that she&amp;#39;s been here for 25 years. &amp;nbsp;That&amp;#39;s the only personal information we exchanged, I think. I could feel that she understood what I was saying. That felt good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t know what happened in between, but before I could realize, I was already in her bed, lying next to her slowly aging body, wide eyed, listening to the squeaks of the slowly revolving fan. She loud snores did help to fill the otherwise silent room. Getting up, I decided to make some coffee for her, as that did seem appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I instantly regretted the decision to have done what I did because it seemed really obvious that it was a one time affair that wasn&amp;#39;t going to last. Also, I felt a tingling sensation deep down that somehow what I did was gravely wrong. I tried diverting my thoughts and focus on the now, as often my psychiatrist told me to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The refrigerator had all sorts of pictures , the ones had children, probably hers, multiple men and paintings that evoked feelings of longing and loneliness. Or maybe that was just how I felt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One picture though, brought on a sense of familiarity. The woman holding a baby, young enough to be the same age as my 2 year old, having a bright smile on her face. She looked considerably young. But the baby had eerily similar features as to his son and that disturbed me a bit. Comparing pictures unsettled me even more. Still trying to stop my imagination from running wild, I took a seat by the kitchen window, and closed my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This is not what you think it is, this is not what you think it is. Just a coincidence, calm down&amp;quot;, I kept on chanting these words to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, on hearing the fridge door open, my eyes darted towards that direction. I saw her, still naked, leaning on, searching for something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost uncontrollably, I started asking her trivial questions related to her life, like if she was an alcoholic, had trust issues, run away from home at the age of 22 to elope with someone, and then leaving him and his son, abruptly, when things didn&amp;#39;t seem to work out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I asked for her first husband&amp;#39;s name. On hearing what she said, I was still unsure because coincidences do happen and this might&amp;#39;ve been one, but I didn&amp;#39;t want to know more. Quickly grabbing onto my belongings, I exited her house, without saying goodbye. A tinge of guilt had taken over me and I wanted to forget it as soon as possible. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, I don&amp;#39;t know what happened, instead of making it straight to the station, I decided to roam around the city, knowing very well that my train left in 5 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 15 minutes remaining, I decided to go where I was a day ago now, a park by the railway station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could hear the sound of the burning wood, breaking the silence where I stood. Even the crickets were awfully quiet, and the trees refused to sway like they used to before. I could see her at a distance from where I stood, moonlight making her wrinkled body shine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should leave now, I thought. I shouldn&amp;#39;t be here, this is fucked up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, a part of me was shouting, &amp;quot;fucked up is good. You love fucked up. You don&amp;#39;t regret what you did a bit!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;#39;t block it anymore. I knew I wasn&amp;#39;t blocking the feelings of guilt or regret, I was blocking the intense lust for the woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran. Hard. Fast. Towards what I thought I deserve, forgetting about everything that was in this world. I ran towards her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artwork by-&lt;br /&gt;Jeniffer Maria&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/fiction/2016/10/12/shh-come-here.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/fiction/2016/10/12/shh-come-here.html</guid>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sky is the limit</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Sky is the limit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;poetry,1 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is nothing, but loads of limits,&lt;br /&gt;
Speed limit on Roads, word limit on Boards,&lt;br /&gt;
Distance limit in Relations and tummy limit for Foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blessed are those, who excel within limits.&lt;br /&gt;
Doomed are the Devils, who selfishly break limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Survival of the Fittest- a proverb that enlightens me.&lt;br /&gt;
Care for the poor my Mother tells me,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I aim to get, Dream is the limit,&lt;br /&gt;
If I aim to give, Sky is the limit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I, Me and Myself and all the modern world blows&lt;br /&gt;
You, We and all of Us, I would propose&lt;br /&gt;
Cry and You cry alone.&lt;br /&gt;
Laugh and the World laughs with you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t count the number of laughs you had in a day,&lt;br /&gt;
Tot up the tears, you wiped from the sad face&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sky is the limit for Brutality&lt;br /&gt;
Sky is also the limit for Humanity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tensions, Difficulties, Temptations, Struggles and Confrontations&lt;br /&gt;
If you look at the dark side, life is all about Struggles&lt;br /&gt;
Every person has a Mountain to climb&lt;br /&gt;
But, take one step at a time, the  journey will be sublime&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s world, there is absolutely no limit,&lt;br /&gt;
For competition, contests-you certainly have to win it!&lt;br /&gt;
There are quite a few, who have raced ahead of others,&lt;br /&gt;
But it’s only a matter of time, then no one will bother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no limit for anything, it’s a race against time,&lt;br /&gt;
You have to keep holding on to every single dime,&lt;br /&gt;
Sky is the limit- a quote well-known,&lt;br /&gt;
And through the world’s competition, it is clearly shown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Raunak Kapur&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/10/05/sky-is-the-limit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/10/05/sky-is-the-limit.html</guid>
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>All Along The Watchtower-An Analysis</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;All Along The Watchtower: An Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Life,2 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I start with the article, I want to you ask yourself :
What is the purpose of writing songs or poetry? Is it to preach, or just express yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think we&amp;rsquo;ll ever have a definitive answer to that, but I can assure to you that I&amp;rsquo;ve heard some music and read some poetry which offer me more context and meaning than complete novels, discourses on philosophies or TED talks. Among such works of art is a song dear to me. It&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;lsquo;All Along The Watchtower&amp;rsquo; by Bob Dylan from his rather &amp;lsquo;out-of-the-blue&amp;rsquo; album &amp;lsquo;John Wesley Harding (1967)&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While recuperating from a motorcycle accident, Bob Dylan wrote several songs for the album. It can easily be told that John Wesley Harding is his most unique album. Keep in mind that 1967 was the same time when The Beatles came out with &amp;ldquo;Sgt. Pepper&amp;rsquo;s Lonely Hearts Band&amp;rdquo; , which was &amp;lsquo;acoustically fulfilling&amp;rsquo; , with extravagant musical pieces and even Dylan said that they were &amp;lsquo;very indulgent&amp;rsquo; . On the other hand this album by Dylan did away with all the epic ballads and was recorded with sparse instrumentations. Dylan calls it the first &amp;lsquo;Biblical Rock Album&amp;rsquo;, which is indeed true not because of the tone of the album but the lyrical content of the album as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the lyrics to &amp;lsquo;All Along The Watchtower&amp;rsquo; :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=In6gCrGeZfA&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;lyrics.png&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/q7OzK69S2jl-s3xA3dN5ZVkHtuTiPJYA1qfFp3XNTAnETHJQnzve5NpS2_QQLVeOTkWrxILG2gnhnPhHTSk7tWLLalUbohu1C8TxhMRsU7ynBlg47j56gdQEOQkC6uIpgr2g_mml&quot; style=&quot;height:318px; width:566px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12 sentences, 130 words and a lifetime of deciphering the meanings!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you can notice is the non-linear nature of the song. It starts in the middle of a conversation, and the last stanza should chronologically be in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bob Dylan commented&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I haven&amp;#39;t fulfilled the balladeers&amp;#39;s job. A balladeer can sit down and sing three songs for an hour and a half... it can all unfold to you. These melodies on John Wesley Harding lack this traditional sense of time. As with the third verse of &amp;quot;The Wicked Messenger&amp;quot;, which opens it up, and then the time schedule takes a jump and soon the song becomes wider... The same thing is true of the song &amp;quot;All Along the Watchtower&amp;quot;, which opens up in a slightly different way, in a stranger way, for we have the cycle of events working in a rather reverse order.&amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_Along_the_Watchtower#cite_note-10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the original album version, the song starts with a high-pitched harmonica and a simple guitar riff which gives the effect of a unfaltering, unwavering force in motion, almost pushing you towards an abyss, with no turning back. This song is the most performed Dylan song in live performances, be it by Dylan , Jimi Hendrix, Eddie Vedder or Lenny Kravitz!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a subject of great discussion about the intertextuality of the lyrics and the allusions it makes. The third stanza echoes directly from the Book of Isiah, where the prophet Isiah tells about the fall of the Neo-Babylonian Empire and describes how it&amp;rsquo;s heading to an inevitable doom! There is often a dichotomy of opinions about the identities of the abovementioned &amp;lsquo;Joker&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Thief&amp;rsquo; in the song. It is often told that the &amp;lsquo;Joker&amp;rsquo; here is an allusion to Jesus Christ, the son of God,as and when he is about to be crucified. He laments about the misfortunes caused by the ignorance of the people in the Kingdom of God, and the &amp;lsquo;Thief&amp;rsquo; here refers to the thief who was crucified alongside Jesus for thievery. The dialogue between them is a silent commentary on our fool-hardiness and the lightness with which lead our life. Another popular opinion about the allusions is that both the &amp;lsquo;Joker&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Thief&amp;rsquo; &amp;nbsp;are both the thieves that were crucified along with Jesus. One of the thieves rebuked the other &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t you fear God even when you have been sentenced to die? We deserve to die for our crimes, but this man (Jesus) hasn&amp;rsquo;t done anything wrong.&amp;rdquo;(Luke 23:40, 41). There&amp;rsquo;s also a crazy theory that the Joker here is Dylan himself, for having squandering all his political significance and earning the hatred of the Country Purists by going all electric. The &amp;lsquo;Thief&amp;rsquo; is supposedly Elvis Presley, presumably because he &amp;lsquo;stole&amp;rsquo; the fame and reputation of a predominantly African-American music genre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the opinion that I believe that justify the lyrics of the song are between the two Babylonians in the book of Revelation, one who wants to stay with the falling Empire and one who chooses to adhere to the flow of time and adapts himself, renouncing all old glory and tradition. Now let&amp;rsquo;s breakdown the lyrics and seek to understand it, line by line. Stay with me, things might &amp;lsquo;inevitably&amp;rsquo; go south.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;i&gt;There must be some way out of here,&amp;rdquo; said the joker to the thief&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marking this timeless conversation, is the introduction of the two riders, who are presumably the two approaching riders from the crossroads as said in the final stanza, given that this song has a reverse chronological order. By saying so, the Joker gives us an exposition into the fact that he is trapped in the worldly chaos and nothing makes sense to him anymore. He is seeking a way to &amp;lsquo;escape&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;surrender&amp;rsquo; , apparently to the Almighty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;i&gt;There is so much confusion, I can&amp;rsquo;t find no relief&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He enhances and elaborates the pain that the Joker is going through. By Aristotelian philosophy, this is a classic case of confusion of thought. The joker uses this as a pretext to repent, he is confused by the complicated, convoluted things happening at the Cross, a perfect Babel of tongues. He can&amp;rsquo;t figure out his own moral code and can&amp;rsquo;t determine what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;i&gt;Businessmen drink my wine, plowmen dig my earth&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Businessmen is a rather modern word while Plowmen has a more ancient undertone. Thereby, Dylan lets us know of the timelessness of this song and how the conflict is forever present, irrespective of the time or the people. I personally think that Dylan parodies the strength of God by saying that the &amp;lsquo;wine&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;earth&amp;rsquo; belongs to &amp;lsquo;me&amp;rsquo;. Therefore, it can be assumed that Joker is none other than the son of God, Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;i&gt;None of them along the line know what any of it is worth&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tells us that all the wealth and riches of Babylon will be destroyed in a single moment. The businessmen and merchants, who became wealthy by selling her these things, terrified by her great torment. They, including the joker, will weep and cry out to all those standing by as if they were saying so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, this song embodies of the &amp;lsquo;corruption&amp;rsquo; in the morality of the crowds and how traditions, cultures, knowledge, everything gets overturned again and again. The real crisis in life comes when choosing sides, when taking decisions. It questions the very fabric of the Divine and alerts of the inevitable doom we&amp;rsquo;re heading towards! Bob Dylan, a prophet in my opinions, makes us realize that we are to choose our own decision and more values. He asks us to live &amp;#39;authentically&amp;#39; and know that we are going to annhilate, either by war or by a natural disaster. He urges us to grab on to whatever we can and grab it fast. Such is music, or any art for that matter. It entertains us, makes us question everything, teaches us and then enlightens us. If there&amp;#39;s any song which has made you think a lot, let us know and we&amp;#39;ll add it to our playlist!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Rohan Mishra&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/life/2016/10/02/all-along-the-watchtower-an-analysis.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/life/2016/10/02/all-along-the-watchtower-an-analysis.html</guid>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Phoenix in You</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;The Phoenix in You&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Poetry,1 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now I am hanging by a thread.&lt;br /&gt;
I can travel up but the heat will scorch me or I can fall down into the abyss.&lt;br /&gt;
But here in the middle it feels good. There is still hope. No extremities. You would think its good.&lt;br /&gt;
But no , it&amp;#39;s even worse. It&amp;#39;s the sweet poison which slowly erodes all your senses and then all you will ever be able to do is just hang there.&lt;br /&gt;
But you can make a bold and brave choice.&lt;br /&gt;
You can fall down below or you can travel up.&lt;br /&gt;
It will surely break you.&lt;br /&gt;
But from those pieces, you can build a new you.&lt;br /&gt;
It will be difficult.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
But it&amp;#39;s a welcome change.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
-Tanmay Pal&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/07/21/the-phoenix-in-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/07/21/the-phoenix-in-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happiness is</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Happiness is&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Poetry,1 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bright, pink.&lt;br /&gt;
Fluffy, moist and lovely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Filled with air ,&lt;br /&gt;
within and without.&lt;br /&gt;
A fleeting sweet taste,&lt;br /&gt;
a scarlet tongue&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
And sticky gums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cotton candy for two,&lt;br /&gt;
Or one, the memory of two.&lt;br /&gt;
A beach walk in July,&lt;br /&gt;
Drenched clothes&lt;br /&gt;
And Sticky hair.&lt;br /&gt;
-&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/rohan.mishra.94&quot;&gt;Rohan Mishra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/07/20/happiness-is.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/07/20/happiness-is.html</guid>
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Terribly Uninteresting Tale</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;A Terribly Uninteresting Tale&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Fiction,3 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People. People everywhere. Look to the right, left, ahead, backwards, upwards, everywhere just people. It&amp;rsquo;s terribly annoying to be around people sometimes. If there are so many people, the voices get jumbled up and all you hear is a not so gentle hiss and hum of different voices, juxtaposed together. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to eavesdrop conversations when you cannot hear comprehensible phrases. Terrible.&lt;br /&gt;
So, I sit on a bench, near an intersection. It&amp;rsquo;s around 6 o&amp;#39; clock in the evening, and there are literally a hundred people around me. There&amp;rsquo;s a friend with me, and he too is talking, but I can&amp;rsquo;t hear him.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m searching for someone.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
She&amp;rsquo;ll be here, I think to myself. I have to do this today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been contemplating about talking to this one girl for the past few days. Okay, I admit, a year, to be exact. Every time I see her, hell, every time I see any new girl that I like, I freeze and am unable to talk. I&amp;rsquo;ve researched about it, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s a disease. The internet tells me it&amp;rsquo;s a mental construct of some sort, but you can&amp;rsquo;t believe everything that&amp;rsquo;s on the internet, can you now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look at my wrist watch. The smaller dial is on 6 and the larger one is somewhere between 5 and 10. Feeling agitated, I start stomping my foot on the ground continually, much to the annoyance of the girl standing next to me. I look up to her.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
I notice she has black hair tied up like a bun, she&amp;rsquo;s wearing this unusually dark pinkish coloured tee, a strand of her hair falling right in front of her left eye. Her face is beautifully constructed, I observe but the expression she has is really not that pleasing. She&amp;rsquo;s talking to someone on her phone and looking at me at the same time, the same look I get from my mother when I do something stupid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
I look down and stop stomping my foot. Then I contemplate about all the stupid things I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
A snap of my friend&amp;rsquo;s fingers brings back my consciousness. I look up to see him looking at me, inquisitively. His unusually wrinkly eyes pry on mine, almost invading my personal space.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo; I ask.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;We have to go, it&amp;rsquo;s getting late.&amp;rdquo; he replies.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Yes yes, wait, she&amp;rsquo;ll be here, then we&amp;rsquo;ll go&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Damn it, I can&amp;rsquo;t stay here. Looking at so many pretty girl depresses me&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Then go talk to one&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Like you can&amp;rdquo; he says, rolling his eyes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;I will, today. Just let her come&amp;rdquo; I say, my eyes, probably, are beaming.&lt;br /&gt;
He stands up and walks towards a shady looking corner. I don&amp;rsquo;t notice where he goes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
Now my eyes search for her. I can&amp;rsquo;t say I&amp;rsquo;m patient right now, hell I&amp;rsquo;m panicking like something. A deer, or zebra, waiting for a lion to pounce on it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
Suddenly, the whole space that my eyes can look at turns red. Completely. I can&amp;rsquo;t see because it&amp;rsquo;s out of focus. On shutting them tight and opening them, I notice a red bus has invaded my vision. I see that it goes to my locality. I look to where my friend stood a minute before to see he&amp;rsquo;s walking towards the bus.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Hey, wait, she might come!&amp;rdquo; I say&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Man, I&amp;rsquo;m tired. I&amp;rsquo;m going&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Wait up&amp;rdquo; I say, but not before I inspect my surroundings, one last time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I see her, with three of her friends, walking merrily, she&amp;rsquo;s wearing this light-ish blue tee that just makes her stand out from the bland colours around her. Honestly, I don&amp;rsquo;t even notice her friends.&lt;br /&gt;
But then my mind decides to plot against me.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;She doesn&amp;rsquo;t know who you are, stop thinking and get on the bus&amp;rdquo;, it says.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
I never think logically when it comes love, but right now, I feel my brain is right. I have no right to be around her, she doesn&amp;rsquo;t care. She doesn&amp;rsquo;t know me.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
I step on the bus, hanging right by the edge, looking on as she walks away from me. I contemplate getting off, but just at that moment, the bus starts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
I sigh and fully get inside it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll talk to her tomorrow&amp;rdquo;, my mind consoles me.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
I wish I would, I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/santrupta.mishra.3&quot;&gt;Santrupta Mishra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/fiction/2016/07/19/a-terribly-uninteresting-tale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/fiction/2016/07/19/a-terribly-uninteresting-tale.html</guid>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lost</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Lost&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Poetry,1 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the laps of the calm waves engulfing the rapids, inundating my feet.&lt;br /&gt;
In the labyrinth of clouds enveloping the winds, silencing my shambolic head.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
In the morass of trees in an embrace so tight, impeding the glimpses the sky steals at me.&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, I&amp;#39;m lost,&lt;br /&gt;
In a lust so deep it consumes my existence for a thirst to wander.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100004731557281&quot;&gt;Shubhi Srivastava&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/07/18/lost.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/07/18/lost.html</guid>
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Night in the Train</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;A Night in the Train&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Romance,3 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up with a start. It was dark, but the person standing in front of me was someone who I&amp;rsquo;d probably never forget.&lt;br /&gt;
It had been a long time since we last talked, I thought. Yet, here she was, standing in front of me. I sat up and shifted on my berth, to make space for her. I&amp;rsquo;d always loved train journeys, but the thought of sharing it with someone who meant so much to me brought a smile to my face. I had never expected this to happen on this college trip in my wildest dreams.&lt;br /&gt;
I tried to hide it but she probably caught me in the act. She sat in front of me, looking to make a conversation. My gaze was fixed on her face. You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call it pretty, but yes, she was beautiful. With her round, deep-brown chocolate eyes and a triangular face, she looked mesmerizing.&lt;br /&gt;
I said, &amp;rdquo;After all that happened, here you are.&amp;rdquo; I believed that the spark, the chemistry was lost between us, I was wrong. She stared right into my eyes and then looked outside the window. Searching for answers in the unknown. She asked, &amp;rdquo;Do you still love me the same way you used to?&amp;rdquo; I replied back with a nod.&lt;br /&gt;
There was a time when I was the one asking all the questions. Why me? But I thought you loved me? Why did you play with my emotions? Such questions clouded my mind at all times. It was her turn to ask questions. Looking me straight in the eyes, she asked, &amp;rdquo;What happened to us, Rahul? There was a time when we used to talk all day long.&amp;rdquo; She continued, &amp;rdquo;It was all so good. You enjoyed my company and I enjoyed yours. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t a topic left which we hadn&amp;rsquo;t talked about. We quenched each other&amp;rsquo;s thirst of a good conversation. A genuine company. Someone who would care for all the stuff other people didn&amp;rsquo;t care about. Someone who would care about me just as much as I cared about him.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Why did you have to fuck up?&amp;rdquo; She asked. Those words sank in like a blade to my heart. Only I knew how much I missed her. Those late-night conversations, those playful rebuttals. All I wanted her to know was that I still cared.&lt;br /&gt;
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t the first time I was hearing this question. My past had been an unfortunate eyewitness of all my screw-ups. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know when to give in. When to close my mouth to save a relationship. It had cost me dearly. In my own self-righteous way, I always thought I was doing the right thing. What I missed was, I was probably just hurting the other person.&lt;br /&gt;
While all of this was going on in my head, I spoke nothing. Because the truth is, I had no proper explanation for why I did what I did. That&amp;rsquo;s what I always did. I fucked up. What remained was my love, I still adored her. Not one day, one moment passes by that I didn&amp;rsquo;t hope or want for her to be by my side. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t matter anymore. My face was a clear reflection of my thoughts, the wrinkles on my forehead were waves formed by the storm raging inside my head. What I wanted to say, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t. What I wanted her to know, she could read on my face. She looked into my eyes and it felt as if she could stare deep down into my soul. All my fears, insecurities, lies and secrets, she now knew.&lt;br /&gt;
I finally mustered up the courage to say something. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry&amp;rdquo;, is all I said. But a voice came from within and I continued, &amp;rdquo;I am sorry for being such a jerk. Sorry for hurting you, demeaning you and not being there for you. I know I&amp;rsquo;m a piece of work but that&amp;rsquo;s just who I am. I never meant for this to happen. I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to say a lot more. But you already know how I feel about you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
She didn&amp;rsquo;t say anything, just shifted a bit and sat beside me. I could see her face clearly now. I could feel her warmth. It was the best feeling in the world, to be near her. I felt protected. I kept my hand on hers, almost instinctively. She didn&amp;rsquo;t oppose and I let it rest. I looked at her, trying to make out what was going on inside her head. But her face was expressionless, eyes staring in another direction. She was lost in deep thought. &amp;ldquo;I love you&amp;rdquo;, I said, almost in a whisper but loud enough for her to hear. She finally looked me in the eyes and said ,&amp;rdquo;I love you too.&amp;rdquo; I wanted to cry, to laugh, to scream and to be silent at the same time. But most of all, I just wanted to embrace this moment.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Lie besides me&amp;rdquo;, I said. She obliged. Moonlight was flowing in from the windows now, illuminating her face. It was just inches away from mine. Although none of us spoke anything, our eyes could hardly keep quiet. They were my weakness. Her round, brown eyes staring into mine. I could have hoped for that moment to last forever but my mind was busy thinking about her. After a long time, i felt at ease. She was my comfort zone. It was our zone now. I kept my hand on her waist and pulled her closer. My actions took her by surprise, but she seemed happy. A small smile now creeped up her previously expressionless face. &amp;ldquo;I won&amp;rsquo;t ever push you for a relationship&amp;rdquo;, I said. &amp;ldquo;But now, I want one&amp;rdquo;, was her reply.&lt;br /&gt;
I was still for a moment, weighing the words which had just come out of her mouth. I was instantly thinking about the consequences, letting the truth to sink in. I stared right into her eyes and then at her lips. Her perfectly shaped, full lips. She got the message. My lips went straight for hers. All the passion just came pouring out. The world came to a halt; that moment was my singularity. I could taste her on the tip of my tongue. All that she wanted to say, all that was left unsaid, all her insecurities, I could read.&lt;br /&gt;
I put my arms around her waist and pulled her in my warm embrace. I could feel her heart beating just inches away from mine. We broke the kiss and stared hard into each other&amp;rsquo;s eyes. Thinking about the ramifications of our actions. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t matter anymore. My hands slowly brushed her cheeks and pulled her in for another kiss. Her hands went straight for my hair, it was even more passionate now, almost animalistic. Our tongues entwined as if they were dancing to a ballad. Our heartbeats now formed an almost harmonious rhythm. It was then that I realised that people search for salvation all their lives and that I had found mine.&lt;br /&gt;
- Tanmay Pal&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/romance/2016/07/18/a-night-in-the-train.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/romance/2016/07/18/a-night-in-the-train.html</guid>
        
        <category>romance</category>
        
        
        <category>romance</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When The Fuckboy Falls in Love</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;When The Fuckboy Falls in Love&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Fiction,3 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;As she bit my lip, I let out a small hiss through my teeth. Should I, should I not? I gripped her tighter. I think I should. So I made my hands go further down the slight curve of her body trying to stop where I wanted to.&lt;br /&gt;
And I was stupefied by an unsettling realisation. I went with the shouldn&amp;#39;t. I didn&amp;#39;t put my hands over the swell of her chest.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
Just a little squeeze of her tiny waist and I mentally laughed for me, Nakul Sachdev, a guy who never thought twice before starting a hot make out with my hands all over the girl&amp;#39;s assets, was now rejoicing in the little curves of this girl&amp;#39;s waist. She had ignited in me a lust, a lust so new it dripped with a longing of her presence and presence only. No hanky-panky, no dirty businesses. Just her, sitting, singing in her husky voice, or merely laugh at the silliest of my jokes with her slight body cosied up in the car seat beside me. I don&amp;#39;t even mind her feet being up, the black thread anklet being the centre of my attention ignoring all the childhood scars she was so afraid to show.&lt;br /&gt;
Her innocence would have an effect so profound on me, I never knew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being her first kiss is glorious enough, I won&amp;#39;t let myself go down the same old routine I share with the girls I&amp;#39;ve had. Not with this one. She is a woman&lt;br /&gt;
A true woman. And I&amp;#39;ll wait for her. (Her begging me is also a fantasy though).&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone of you is knowledgeable enough to understand this new terminology seeing it has taken the social media like a storm. Fuckboy. For those of you not that fortunate, it means a male who acts, lies, cheats, enacts, pretends to be someone else, has multiple identities and alibis, all in the aim of getting into a girl&amp;#39;s pants.&lt;br /&gt;
Nowadays, the increase in number of short term relationships or as we call them, friends with benefits; the new wave of online dating; polygamy when the other person doesn&amp;#39;t know about it (for laymen, cheating) have conditioned the heads of girls to a level that even a guy asking the directions to a place with a smile on his face will be tagged as a fuckboy for any lady. Maybe he is that, maybe he loves this life and the sense of freedom it provides him. And obviously, it&amp;#39;s a small world and the reputations of this category of men follows them everywhere.&lt;br /&gt;
The real complication occurs when this gentleman actually falls in love. The reputation won&amp;#39;t help you now, will it? And a girl, no matter how naive she is and how this guy is a dream for her and how she is head over heels for this guy, won&amp;#39;t give in, won&amp;#39;t ever trust him when he confesses his feelings for you. It might be another act to aid him to get into her pants. So what do we do now?&lt;br /&gt;
The answer is simple. Do what you never did boy, befriend her. The idea of taking someone out for a coffee or pancakes is so bizarre for us that the amazing outcomes of these 3 hours you spend without looking at your phones have obliterated from our minds. Loving someone means loving the person in front of you, not the girls he did it with, not the people he met, not the number of swipes he got on Tinder. It is just a leap of faith girls, you need to overcome your fears. Also, there is always an option of going diabolical and setting his house on fire if he does what you feared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I will stick to this, you will not find the better half unless you have at least three failed relationships. And what if he was a fuckboy indeed. You made him stop, you made him leave the lifestyle he adopted for years, you made him concentrate on one centre of his universe, and that&amp;#39;s you, take pride in that, keep your head high and go for it. It is okay to let go. In this bedlam of a universe, it is only you who can protect yourself and only you who will harm yourself. Hence, what will be your golden word? Happiness or Conjecture? I leave it to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100004731557281&quot;&gt;Shubhi Srivastava&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/fiction/2016/07/17/when-the-fuckboy-falls-in-love.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/fiction/2016/07/17/when-the-fuckboy-falls-in-love.html</guid>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
