<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Wordsmiths</title>
    <description>Blog and Content Production Company
</description>
    <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://thewordsmiths.xyz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 21:38:53 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 21:38:53 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Untitled</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Untitled&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Poetry)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Here I am again&lt;br /&gt;
Quill in hand, a diary in front&lt;br /&gt;
Ready to pen down&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new testament&lt;br /&gt;
To my worry and woes&lt;br /&gt;
To my insecurities and lows&lt;br /&gt;
To all that I fear and also hold dear&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the one that got away and to the one whom I let go&lt;br /&gt;
The clock starts to tick&lt;br /&gt;
Thoughts don&amp;rsquo;t leave the crevices of my brain&lt;br /&gt;
And seep onto the page&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To paint the pictures that I think&lt;br /&gt;
The smoke goes stale, of the last drag that I missed thinking of you&lt;br /&gt;
Trying to find my muse in you&lt;br /&gt;
Trying to muster up a rhyme from your being&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying hard! To find words.&lt;br /&gt;
Then it dawns upon me; my subjects are long dead&lt;br /&gt;
My verses are idle and repressed&lt;br /&gt;
And me? Stuck, the same place as yesterday&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what&amp;rsquo;s this occasional misfit to do?&lt;br /&gt;
Should I not feel?&lt;br /&gt;
No. It&amp;rsquo;s not that I don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;br /&gt;
Know that nostalgia&amp;rsquo;s not for me; for I&amp;rsquo;ll never&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let go.&lt;br /&gt;
Should I not think?&lt;br /&gt;
No. It&amp;rsquo;s what I do&lt;br /&gt;
That defines my self for you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To consume.&lt;br /&gt;
Should I just give up?&lt;br /&gt;
No. For some fights are better fought&lt;br /&gt;
When you&amp;rsquo;re about to lose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here I am; a little bitter,&lt;br /&gt;
A little better.&lt;br /&gt;
Ready for another battle.&lt;br /&gt;
Quill in hand, a diary in front&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ready to pen down&lt;br /&gt;
A new testament.&lt;br /&gt;
-&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/tanmay.pal.97&quot;&gt;Tanmay Pal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/07/13/untitled.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/07/13/untitled.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mother&#39;s Love</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Mother&#39;s Love&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Thriller, 6 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well the morning was complete, there were tears on the steering wheel dripping on the seat..”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was awoken from a deep sleep with Alex’s wistful voice, asking his girl to break his nose, filtering into my dreams. My eyes still felt heavy, and they opened slowly. I blinked them to completely dispel the fogginess that marred my vision. The sight that greeted me was completely foreign – pasty walls enclosed the bed I was currently imprisoned in, while IV drips were attached to my arms, and the only thing covering my body besides the clean white sheets was a thin gown. I tried getting up, but heaviness crept around in my head again, stopping me from doing so. Deciding that I was better off in a sleeping position, I opted to gather my bearings in that state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Television in the corner playing the Monkeys’ concert – check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another lost soul in the room – nah I’m all alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My phone – MY PHONE! Looking around, I found my phone on the bedside table, but sadly lacked the strength in reaching for it. Giving up, I settled more snugly against the covers, and tried to figure out how I ended up here in the first place. With a head injury though, it seemed unlikely that I would be able to recall it all.
Wait, didn’t I have any family members waiting up on me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never really had a good relation with my family – my mother, who always blames me for the most trivial of problems occurring around, my father, who always sides with his wife, and ends up giving me a pitying smile, and my younger brother, the apple of my parents’ eyes. Yeah, I’m not really considered a part of the family, and rumour has it (heard my relatives talking about it the other day) that I’m the unwanted child; a girl who was born into a household which desired a son, desperately. Well, at least god ‘blessed’ them with one later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My 10 year old brother has it all; he just has to merely whisper what he wants, and my folks granted it. If I wanted something, I was usually given hand-me-downs or nothing at all. It’s a wonder my parents even gave me basic amenities, like education and all, seeing they treat me quite indifferently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, their apathy towards me resulted in me being a wild-child. Getting into reckless activities, drinking limitlessly - they didn’t really care what I was up to. So why not I live my life to the fullest? That didn’t mean I was letting my studies slip away. Oh no. I made sure I got straight A’s and kept up with my co-curriculars, they were my ticket to scholarship and a good uni, and a passage out of this hell hole called ‘family’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hearing some voices coming towards my ward, I quickly pretended to be asleep. I heard the door open suddenly, and a man’s voice filtered through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The accident resulted in severe blood loss. Her head received most of the impact. Thank goodness for air-bags, they lessened the severity of the damage.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Will she wake up soon, doctor? She’s been out for almost a whole day after the operation”, a woman’s voice, my mother’s chimed in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“She should. It’s a miracle we found a donor real quick. It becomes really difficult to save them when the blood type doesn’t match with the kin and we have to put a word across for an available donor. We don’t get volunteers real quick. And our city has limited blood banks. All the more reason for our government to step up their game and do something about it.” The man, apparently the doctor who treated me, adds the last part with a short laugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donor, who wasn’t family?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Can I stay in here for while doctor?”, my mother asks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Take as long as you’d like, Mrs. Aggarwal,” the doctor replies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hearing a set of footsteps leave the room, I felt soft hands caressing my cheeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh Naina, I’m sorry, so, so sorry. I shouldn’t have let this get out of hand. You don’t deserve my animosity. Please wake up, and I’ll be sure to make it up to you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slowly opening my eyes, I turned to face her. “What happened to me?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You were involved in a car accident, my dear.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dear? Damn I must’ve hit my head real hard, because obviously you wouldn’t really use that endearment now, would you woman?”, I reply scathingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh honey, I’m really sorry. Can we please move on from the last episode?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What happened last time?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well we...we were fighting, and I…it just...I couldn’t help it my dear...it came out of my mouth quite involuntarily..obviously hearing this anybody would storm out and get into a reckless accident..let’s not rehash it, yeah?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Just spit it out woman, I’m sure it wouldn’t be as bad as you treated me the last 18 years of my life!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reeling a bit from my scratchy yet slightly raised voice, she continued, “I’d said I wished I’d miscarried you somehow when I discovered I was pregnant with you.”
Taking a deep breath, I turned away from her. She continued wistfully, “I was already in my third trimester when I discovered that you were about to be born. Abortion in our country is illegal after this time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixing her with a glare, I said “so, a car accident? I wonder why god sent me back here. Maybe he didn’t want me to die without me clearing up a few things up yeah?” On the last few words, my voice died down a bit and then I started coughing in a frenzy. My mother quickly got up from her seat beside my bed a got me a glass of water. She got me into a sitting position, rubbing my back as she did so. Still surprised by her tender gestures, I drank the glass of water offered to me without any protest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I shouldn’t have alienated you..of course none of this is your fault..shouldn’t take my anger out on you..I promise to make it up to you..” My mother started off with her nervous chatter yet again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting the glass aside, I said, “it&#39;s okay, you don&#39;t have to explain. I&#39;m the unwanted child right? You guys never wanted a girl, and I came along. You don&#39;t have to justify your medieval mind-set.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I..uh..what? Who told you that?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shrugging my shoulders, I said “Overheard some people who were discussing our family matters.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No..that’s not the case...I..you just had a massive accident..we’ll discuss this later..now’s not the right time..I..”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Just cut it out! I think I deserve some answers!” I almost screamed at her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I got pregnant with you when I was 19!” She blurted out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t surprised. “Of course they thought of marrying you off real quick.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She continued “Teenage pregnancy isn’t easy. And for a child to be born outside marriage, it’s even more challenging…” she trailed off, unable to meet my eyes by this point.
I opened my mouth, but shut it up. I was too gobsmacked to even say anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a deep breath, she pushed on “I was about your age. Had gone out for lunch one day with few of my friends. As we came out of the restaurant, a bunch men came up to us, and started misbehaving with one of my friends. All of us took a stand against it, but they were relentless. I slapped one of them...they beat me up, took me in their car...and..”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this time, I couldn’t hear further. But she went on, “...my friends tried to follow them, but they drove fast. They took me to an abandoned warehouse, where the men..took turns..”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even she couldn’t continue further. I could taste bile rising up my throat. Taking a deep breath, she said “You were the result..of this..I still don’t know who the actual father is. None of them were caught. I was discarded in the warehouse itself, where the..act..happened. Somehow I managed to get back home.”
I wanted to wretch my guts out by this point, but lack of food made it impossible. Pieces began to fall into place– why me and my mother never got along, and why my blood group didn&#39;t match with either of my parents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nayanika came out of the hospital ward, wiping her eyes out for residual tears in the process. Having lulled Naina back to sleep, she hoped things would go uphill from this moment on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Did she take the bait?”, her husband, Sameer asks her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“She did seem to. She was always such a tender heart, even though she acted otherwise. It was easy to manipulate her.”
“Good. I talked to the party. They&#39;re willing to set the date for as soon as possible. They&#39;ll give us the money on the wedding night. Make sure you set her up in such a way that she agrees to the wedding without batting an eyelid. The money that we’re getting in return will set us up for a long time. It&#39;s time your ‘reckless’ mistakes of the past came to be of some use.” Sameer says with a sardonic smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh as if you weren&#39;t hedonistic enough”, Nayanika replies snidely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sameer just raised his eyebrows. “Just make sure that selling her off is the best decision we ever made.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fin!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Shreya Barua&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/thriller/2016/07/12/mother.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/thriller/2016/07/12/mother.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thriller</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Song of the Muse</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Song of the Muse&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Commentary, 3 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Hold your breath. Don&#39;t fall sideways. Do NOT cross your feet too close, you will fall. Don&#39;t let them know you&#39;re thinking all this. Please.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered the story behind the meticulous stills of beautiful models in an array of different poses, different backdrops, story, colours, themes, arranged in a manner so perfect you just can&#39;t take your eyes off it? It is actually a melange of efforts by many people all instilled in this one photograph, but in the end, it&#39;s the muse and the photographer that make it alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a dance, it&#39;s a debate, it&#39;s, thus, a truce, it&#39;s a photograph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The models you see and admire aren&#39;t perfect human being prototypes who&#39;ll stand in the manner deemed most perfect. They are like me and you. It takes as little as four seconds for the photographer to settle himself and the camera and thus, accomplish it with the final click. But in those four seconds, a series of dynamic thoughts fluster the muse, taking all out of her to not fall out of the poise because of a difficult pose or most commonly, just anxiety can be the mightiest trigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first shoot is where this anxiety sets in. You might be a lady, a klutz, a perfect specimen of pulchritude, a total goof, or, a diva but in front of the camera, you are a muse. Thus, you&#39;re fixated on ingraining the whole concept in your head and mold your body accordingly completely ignoring the fact that the concept belongs to the brainstorming of a group of complete strangers. You dot the i&#39;s and cross the t&#39;s to a point where the angle of the arch of your brows is scrutinised by you, yourself. But it all goes in vain until you put your heart to it. You look into the camera and stare at it with a reverie that can only belong to a lover you devour yourself into. You look away from it as it is the only one thing that repels you in this world. You taunt it as it is the only tease you have ever enjoyed in your life and that one still sings. It sings the harmony that enlightens the artist behind the camera, enthralls the person looking at the photograph, beatifies the person who believed in you to make their products come to life and it satisfies you, the muse, the only one who can do this dance with the photographer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The anxiety to fulfill the needs of everybody who made you their muse will always be there. It makes sure you don&#39;t get heady and the urge to perform better is unabated. But the assortment of feelings of taking pride in their confidence and gratitude for them to choose you is something that fuels you to go on. You are the answer to his call, a call so abysmal only you&#39;re the answer to it. Maybe Robert Fitzgerald explaining Homer&#39;s Odyssey can explain better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Sing in me, Muse, and through me tell the story..&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Shubhi Srivastava&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/commentary/2016/07/11/muse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/commentary/2016/07/11/muse.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>commentary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Man closes his Eyes</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Man closes his Eyes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Poetry, 6 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A man, old and frail, &lt;br /&gt;
Sitting in this room so dark, &lt;br /&gt;
Closes his eyes to plunge into the past, &lt;br /&gt;
His past, which isn&#39;t so vast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the depths if his mind, &lt;br /&gt;
He finds two children, &lt;br /&gt;
A son and a daughter, no more than twelve, &lt;br /&gt;
Playing in the garden by themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her daughter, a fairy in human form, &lt;br /&gt;
Looks like love getting personified. &lt;br /&gt;
She looks at him, looks terrified, &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Like something is burning, within her heart, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opens her mouth, and the lullaby start, &lt;br /&gt;
&quot;In the land of heavens, there resides a fairy; &lt;br /&gt;
As playful as a little dove. &lt;br /&gt;
With a gentle heart, she is a sky full of stars, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waiting for her moon, waiting for her love.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
Clatter of metal disrupt his music, &lt;br /&gt;
A soldier banging his bars with a rod, &lt;br /&gt;
He comes back to the cell, where he is contained, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He stands up, tall and broad.&lt;br /&gt;
An accomplice enters his room, &lt;br /&gt;
The lawyer, who is going to defend. &lt;br /&gt;
With hand on the old man&#39;s shoulder, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He promises that all his trouble will end.
His hands tremble, in rage and fear &lt;br /&gt;
And his dried up eyes, burst out a tear &lt;br /&gt;
For all these blames, he got to hear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all this pain, he has to bear.&lt;br /&gt;
And he closes his eyes again, &lt;br /&gt;
Her body flashes in front of him, &lt;br /&gt;
With his kitchen knife carved through her heart &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the lullabies in his ears start, &lt;br /&gt;
&quot;In the land of heavens, there resides a fairy; &lt;br /&gt;
As playful as a little dove. &lt;br /&gt;
With a gentle heart, she is a sky full of stars, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waiting for her moon, waiting for her love.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
Within the symphony he hears the claps of wood, &lt;br /&gt;
A wooden hammer on a raid. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He open his eyes to find himself in a courtroom. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He open his eyes, standing on the palisade.&lt;br /&gt;
He looks around, at thoughtless people, &lt;br /&gt;
Faint murmurs, and chatter of a typewriter, &lt;br /&gt;
Lawyers rustling through files and folders, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking to keep the blame upon his shoulders.&lt;br /&gt;
And the man, too old and frail, &lt;br /&gt;
His limbs shiver in fear and rage. &lt;br /&gt;
Rage, arising out of these shackles, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear, of ending his book on this page. &lt;br /&gt;
While, not much life, permits his age. &lt;br /&gt;
Like a bird, who is caught in a cage &lt;br /&gt;
Just the view of sky is no patronage, &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, his freedom lures him &lt;br /&gt;
And fills him with more fear and rage.&lt;br /&gt;
The arguments begin, &lt;/p&gt;
The learned men, blabber their knowledge &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A man approaches with the holy book. &lt;br /&gt;
&quot;Keep your hand on it, and take the pledge&quot; &lt;br /&gt;
Commands his accomplice, in a hushed tone, &lt;br /&gt;
&quot;I pledge in the name of god; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth is all that I shall say.&quot; &lt;br /&gt;
And this won&#39;t be the last lie he will tell this day.&lt;br /&gt;
With that in process, the prosecutor pulls a knife &lt;br /&gt;
Which has dried up blood all through it&#39;s surface, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And his kitchen knife is bound to have his fingerprints,&lt;br /&gt;
The fingerprints, which makes the prosecution&#39;s case.&lt;br /&gt;
His prints and his actions, &lt;br /&gt;
Drag him into a shit hole; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the prosecution &quot;rests&quot; &lt;br /&gt;
While &quot;the defence rests&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
And while his accomplice is trying all he can;&lt;br /&gt;
His gaze wanders to the forensics&#39; table, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find the locket which belonged to her daughter, &lt;br /&gt;
The locket got painted red in her slaughter. &lt;br /&gt;
And, he closes his eyes &lt;br /&gt;
And remembers about the day he gifted her this locket &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How he sneakingly, slid it into her pocket, &lt;br /&gt;
Can&#39;t forget the smile she had, &lt;br /&gt;
Later that evening, he took her to bed.&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, he used to molest his own daughter, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sad truth, on which the world should weep,&lt;br /&gt; 
But, even that brutal act doesn&#39;t provide the courage, &lt;br /&gt;
To murder his own daughter, in her sleep.&lt;br /&gt;
And he pictures his daughter lying next to him, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sweet little lady, with a noble heart, &lt;br /&gt;
The heart which is now carved out. &lt;br /&gt;
And with that, the lullabies start &lt;br /&gt;
&quot;In the land of heavens, there resides a fairy; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As playful as a little dove. &lt;br /&gt;
With a gentle heart, she is a sky full of stars, &lt;br /&gt;
Waiting for her moon, waiting for her love.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;If I may, I would like to call upon, &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deceased lady&#39;s brother&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
And steps upon the palisade, &lt;br /&gt;
Her brother from another mother.&lt;br /&gt;
He is a cruel, little bastard, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a stout body, and a squinted eye. &lt;br /&gt;
He walks out with no remorse of what happened, &lt;br /&gt;
Although he may have seen his sister die. &lt;br /&gt;
As the old man claims that he saw him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was seen walking out of the crime scene, &lt;br /&gt;
&quot;What&#39;s your name? Where were you?&quot; &lt;br /&gt;
And the rest of the questions follow the daily routine.&lt;br /&gt;
The defence presses upon his presence at the scene, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In old man&#39;s favor, the freedom is getting named. &lt;br /&gt;
People get restless. &quot;Order, order!&quot; &lt;br /&gt;
They know that the young man is being falsely framed.&lt;br /&gt;
But, nobody knows what really happened, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prosecution and defence, fight like wild cats embrace.&lt;br /&gt; 
&quot;I was the one who killed her!&quot; &lt;br /&gt;
A man&#39;s confession turned over the turning case.&lt;br /&gt;
A man, old and frail, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With tear on his cheeks and wobbly balance, &lt;br /&gt;
Confesses that he killed his daughter, &lt;br /&gt;
And therefore signs his last chapter.&lt;br /&gt;
And that man, old and frail; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confessed to a heinous crime, &lt;br /&gt;
Wonder, wonder, what&#39;s more heinous, &lt;br /&gt;
The crime itself, or the confession he made.&lt;br /&gt;
With that, he closes his eyes, and the lullaby starts, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;In the land of heavens, there resides a fairy; &lt;br /&gt;
As playful as a little dove. &lt;br /&gt;
With a gentle heart, she is a sky full of stars, &lt;br /&gt;
Waiting for her moon, waiting for her love.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;© The Anonymous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/07/10/man-eyes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/07/10/man-eyes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Objectifying women in music</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Objectifying Women in Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Commentary, 6 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was another usual Delhi’s hot summer day and I was out on a drive with my father. I turned on the FM radio. “&lt;i&gt;Mere photo ko seene se yaar…... main to tandoori murgi hu…..&lt;/i&gt;”
“Change the channel. What nonsense are they playing. I don’t understand what has happened to this generation’s taste in music,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another channel played “&lt;i&gt;blue eyes….choti dress me bomb lagdi…&lt;/i&gt;”. Filled with disgust, I turned off the FM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not very fond of music myself. Most of the times, I find myself trying to look for reasons to dislike it even more so that I do not have to listen to it much. Most of my friends literally survive on music. I do not get this idea much. Well, personal choices do vary from person to person. I remember how my friends used to tease me when I would talk to them about a latest song because that song was never latest by the time it fell into my ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been feeling this upsurge to express my disgust and displeasure on this for a long time now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One fine day, I was listening to a song named “brown rang” by the apparent Rap God - Mr. Yo Yo Honey Singh. I am so glad that this song grabbed my attention and I started respecting him. I realised how beneficial this man was to the Indian society that tends to judge the girls based on their appearance. The song starts with telling the girls that their “dusky complexion” is something that is the most sought after aspect in them and they should not worry that they are not “fair”. He moves on and even tells them that these days, boys do not like “fair girls”. He further goes on to explain other aspects of their looks and dressing sense. This song is definitely an “eye opener” for our society and would help in eradicating racism. Great job done, Mr. Singh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women have been seen as a plaything and not even a living thing that could have her own existence, an object that would provide pleasure to men. Their bodies have been made a subject to base the songs on. Most of the songs that top the playlists these days are what we call “item songs”. Bollywood has never been very kind to women and has played a major role in establishing gender biases and gender roles in the modern world. And with the increasing trend of item songs these days, this problem is aggravating. Moreover, we listen to such crap while turning the volume higher up and shouting and singing our lungs out. We don’t bother about this problem for even a second.
Hypocrisy is a major feature of mankind. One day, I find all those high profile feminists protesting against something that they feel is derogatory to women. I am happy when I see them raising this issue against such songs. But, the very next day, I am extremely disappointed when I watch the news channels and find them dancing on such songs in a party held the previous night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not find these songs “entertaining” at all. But these are the ones that grab the most attention. They help the musicians (as they call themselves) to gain monetary profits and hence they continue to compose such filthy songs. We are encouraging these people to continue insulting women by using such derogatory and callous terms. This reflects their mediocre mindsets. But this situation will not change until we stand against them. It is really important that our society begins to understand what is good for its growth and what is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Shreya Garg&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/commentary/2016/07/08/women-music.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/commentary/2016/07/08/women-music.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>commentary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Touch</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Touch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;( &lt;i&gt;Fiction, 3 minute read&lt;/i&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She rushed on the subway. He followed her. Not saying a word to each other. What could they even say? Apparently there was nothing left to talk about. &quot;This couldn&#39;t be the end&quot;, both felt. Walking amidst the sunday flocks, he didn&#39;t lose sight of her even once. &lt;br /&gt;
He couldn&#39;t then, he can&#39;t now. She had always been the apple of his eye. Loving her more than anything else had been his first profession. Even before taking care of his ancestral shop in the suburbs. What salary for this profession, you may ask? Well, her love was much more than any remuneration he could even think of earning! &lt;br /&gt;
When she was sad, he would cry harder. When she was sick, the doctor treated him first. When she had a visit from little friend down south, he would stay by her side throughout. &lt;br /&gt;
People were sure their happiness was a decoy. But to be candid, it was more real than reality could be!&lt;br /&gt;
Defying all speculations of friends and foes, they had been together for ten lovely years. And hoped to continue till their last breath. Afterall, he hadn&#39;t even looked at another girl all these years. As for her, he was the best she could ever hope for. &lt;br /&gt;
But as they say, change is the only constant. Life had been harsh on them. Both of them. Why else would they live to see dreadful days which were yet to come?&lt;br /&gt;
Even before parting, both realized this. Dreadful days to come. Dreadful days to live through. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as she was about to exit the subway, she felt a tap on her shoulder. She skipped a beat. She was so elated at this gentle touch. This had indeed been his best touch till now! Never did she feel so overwhelmed. This touch gave her new hopes. Hopes which could save her from those days. Remember? Dreadful days. Hopes which could save the world from shattering into bits of useless pieces. &lt;br /&gt;
She turned with glee. Her eyes looking straight. Straight into the crowd. He didn&#39;t follow her no more. Nowhere to be seen, as far as her eyes could scan. Maybe it was his way to say goodbye. With a heavy heart and limbs numb, she stood looking through the crowd, hoping he would follow her again, sometime!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/fiction/2016/07/05/touch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/fiction/2016/07/05/touch.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Post-Modern Art is not shit.</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Why Post-Modern Art is not shit.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Commentary, 3 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title of this article is something controversial. I mean, have you seen modern art?! They just put up anything anywhere and ‘oh, my god. Such a genius. The depiction of oppression in the society is palpable in this masterpiece’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uh, excuse me? You felt the oppression from a broken bottle kept on an overturned table?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems ridiculous, doesn’t it? Have you seen Marcel Duchamp’s seminal modern art masterpiece? No? Well, I’m telling you that you have. In 1917, Marcel Duchamp took a porcelain urinal, rotated it 90 degrees, and put it on the ground. That broke the art community. Duchamp said that his intent was to shift the focus of art from physical craft to intellectual interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before aimlessly going ahead, let’s take a step back and ask “What is art?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a good question. What is art? Art is not continuous. It flows through times, conforming to adjust with the mentalities and the culture of the ages. To Plato, art was imitation of nature. Then photographers came and took over that job. In the 20th century, artists like Picasso and Monet came around and they shifted the definition of art from the imitation to the ‘feel’ of nature. Since then, art has been majorly associated with the ‘feel’ of the world we live in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The definition of modern art follows from this. It’s just the feel of the world we live in. The amazingly chaotic, hectic, broken and hard-to-figure-out-messes which art galleries go nuts to display? They’re a reflection of our world. Our crazy world, full of all these modern baits, these metal monsters running on the ground, the metal birds flying in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take Scream. Edvard Munch’s Scream is not your usual beautiful masterpiece. It makes you uncomfortable. It ‘expresses’ the image. It ‘reflects’ the plight of the modern age man. But you know what? That’s your own ‘interpretation’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can still call modern art rubbish. Duchamp’s piece is literally something you piss on. You can say, “Hey! That’s arbitrary! Even I could have done that!” But you didn’t. He did it before you. However simplistic and arbitrary modern art may be, it’s there. The most powerful museums and galleries of the world house it with a religious fervour. It sells for millions. You can call it bullshit. The museums and artists won’t bat an eye. You know why? Because as long as someone dismisses, it is still provocative. Contemporary art has established itself as subversive, radical and challenging. And it must be so. The people are still calling it bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Harsh Pandey&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/commentary/2016/07/05/modern-art.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/commentary/2016/07/05/modern-art.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>commentary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Feel</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Feel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Poetry&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A strong case of feels they say,&lt;br /&gt;
Not at such a crucial time, I pray.&lt;br /&gt;
Thumping in the chest,&lt;br /&gt;
Pressure rising in veins&lt;br /&gt;
With every trough and crest&lt;br /&gt;
The heart starts to break the chains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel, my precious,&lt;br /&gt;
We weren’t meant to hold back.&lt;br /&gt;
Don’t pull the reins; be curious&lt;br /&gt;
Let yourself soar high.&lt;br /&gt;
Love. Cry. Fall. Or break.&lt;br /&gt;
Just don’t regret it at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is a journey,&lt;br /&gt;
Finished by all but enjoyed by the brave.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 20:04:25 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/07/04/feels.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/07/04/feels.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nostalgia</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Nostalgia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Poetry&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single moment, trapped in cellulose&lt;br /&gt;
Or a scent your nose never forgets. &lt;br /&gt;
A taste of your beloved or&lt;br /&gt;
Some view you shared with someone&lt;br /&gt;
Who is no longer there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memories seep through,&lt;br /&gt;
Emotions hit as pulses,&lt;br /&gt;
Then as waves&lt;br /&gt;
Washing you over the cliff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They find their way&lt;br /&gt;
Through your eyes&lt;br /&gt;
Drops turning to waterfall&lt;br /&gt;
You relive it as it once was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remembrance at times high or low&lt;br /&gt;
Is a terrible thing to bear.&lt;br /&gt;
Look forward; don’t cling on to past.&lt;br /&gt;
For that’s how you fare.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 20:04:25 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/07/03/nostalgia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/poetry/2016/07/03/nostalgia.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Fantasy</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;The Fantasy :- &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Thriller, 7 minute read&lt;/i&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creaks of his dilapidated chair echoed in the baronial office work space. There was an eerie silence and the day was cognitively different from typical. Rajat waited for his computer to compile the Java and lazily turned at the digital clock on his grey desk. Two years, three months four day and the 13th hour of hard work, that would soon vanish unaccounted for. He sighed. Soon, sound of heavy footsteps marching right into the office corridor broke his parade of thoughts. Realizing the implication, Rajat hurried out to hail a convoy of corporate patrons, a corporate etiquette, probably. The group that trotted through the narrow corridor was led by a lady he had certainly never seen before. The lady was in a red pencil-skirt, topped by a satin white shirt tucked inside the skirt. She had let her brown cascade tied up in a high bun. There was an unusual charm that ran down her porcelain skin and perfectly beautified delicate features. She wore a white crystal pendant that hung loosely at the edge of her cleavage. As the swarm passed Rajat, she turned sharply to take a look at him. Her look was different and the smirk that momentarily changed the dimensions of her blood red lips was evil. Her eyes had a tinge of seduction and carried an aura of mystery, cold and deep. As they walked into the big conference room, the whispers and the sound of footsteps were gradually replaced by the pin-drop silence.&lt;br /&gt;
As our protagonist resumed his work, he found it hard to resist the thoughts of the anonymous lady he had just had an exchange of expressions with. She was wrapped in an unresolved mystery. It was not particularly scary yet had nothing to entice in a stable human mind but fear and anxiety. She had the essence that commanded attention and a disdain for interference resting in the backdrop. A combination of too many traits, with clarity of none. He had noticed her steps to be too light and fleeting. She didn’t wobble a step despite the sharply pointed heels she wore. There was a degree of perfection she carried that was far from generic. Someone among his colleagues had hinted her to be an ad-hoc for the ailing chairman, and thoughts of her being temporary lingered in his thoughts and saddened a part of his soul.&lt;br /&gt;
A knock interrupted Rajat’s engrossment, and he re-organised himself to save himself from any embarrassment, not very sure if his mentally seduced-self had not affected his physical one in sub consciousness.&lt;br /&gt;
“Arey, aaiye Pandey ji, come in.”, he smiled while gesturing the old clerk to come in, “Who is it now?”&lt;br /&gt;
“The new madam, Sirji, she wants to have a meeting with you”, the old clerk said while trying to flaunt his skills in English.&lt;br /&gt;
Momentarily, his heart stopped beating and the very next moment it bit so vigorously that he could feel his chest puffing in and out. A peculiar sense of ecstasy stretched his lips into a smile and sending him back to a hallucinated engrossment paired with too many questions. He managed to give a slight nod to the clerk. As the latter walked out of the cabin, Rajat turned himself towards the wall with the clock hanging on it.&lt;br /&gt;
Thirty minutes past ten, it said. Rajat smiled and briefed a small introduction, rehearsed it a few more times and started walking out of the cabin with a file in his hand, probably to look a tad more professional.&lt;br /&gt;
He sauntered to Madam’s cabin in order to veil his overwhelm and excitement. On reaching the cabin door, he could notice through the glass that the lady had her gaze fixed on the large antique clock on the textured wall, while her hands played with the white crystal pendant that had the prodigy of embracing her smooth skin. She had let her hair open and thick brown mass of hair fell over her shoulders. She looked obnoxious and intoxicated Rajat pushing him back to his world of secret thoughts.&lt;br /&gt;
“You may come in”, the lady said, slowly drifting her gaze towards Rajat. Her voice was melody. Was there anything about her not par perfection? Or was she a goddess in disguise? What if she actually was an angel without a halo? Umpteen nonsensical fantasies whirred his head as Rajat walked into the cabin, somewhat in trance. He tried looking here and there to save himself from doing anything embarrassing. The cabin had been renovated and it was majorly covered in red, seemingly thematic. A painting of a river of blood flowing, with desiccated bodies lying along the bay line hung behind the lady. It was eerie and awkward and crippled the romance that had lately been coveting Rajat’s senses. Bringing about what the lady commanded, fear. He turned his head to the left and was slightly surprised to see the big antique clock stuck at 9. Before he could raise a question, the only other voice in the room spoke up. “I like it at 9”. Suspense enhanced and fears were a replaced inhibition back in our hero’s mind.&lt;br /&gt;
“I hear you’re one of the most accomplished employees here. You have scored big time. I was curious to know more of you.”&lt;br /&gt;
Rajat managed a smile despite the most bizarre emotions ransacking his courage down the core.&lt;br /&gt;
“How do you like me?” the lady spoke in a manner that was too sharp to be ignored and too polite to be good. Her eyes narrowed as she pierced them into his, somewhat blurring his conscience.&lt;br /&gt;
“You’re beautiful”, Rajat said as he gulped a lump of self-apathy and shame down his throat.&lt;br /&gt;
She smiled and blushed and despite the bewildering fears, Rajat could not resist noticing how ravishing she looked with her cheeks tempting rosy shades of shyness. As he looked on, the lady got up and walked behind him, her steps too light and fleeting.&lt;br /&gt;
“Tell me more”, she whispered, bending upon her shoulders, and letting her long fingers play with the manly chest with a fragile heart underneath.&lt;br /&gt;
“I like the pendant that dangles down your neck”. Clueless of the silence that followed, Rajat apprehensively turned towards the lady, only to be left aghast.&lt;br /&gt;
Streams of black tears ran down the lady’s rosy cheeks.&lt;br /&gt;
“I wanted it red. I like red.” Rajat stared at the petrifying sight that hung over his shoulder, scarcely left with any of his senses. The mystery was unfolding and fears clutched every inch of his soul, making him too gullible to dare, too trapped to escape.&lt;br /&gt;
“Will you make it red?”, the lady spoke in deathly innocence, and before he could frame what had just happened, Rajat could see the charming visage turning beastly, with pale eyes and parched lips, and a growl before long canine teeth pulsated through his veins, draining every ounce of blood in his body. The world darkened around him, as he saw the white crystal turning red, blood red- his blood fulfilling the unfulfilled desires of a scarred soul, an uncanny barter at the cost of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A loud thump shook him off the nap he had slipped into. Rajat looked around and shrugged. His forehead shun with sweat and his face was pale, ironically as an expression of relief. A panoply of emotions gushed through his nerves. He felt like an escapist, a refugee who had liberated himself from the fetters of torture and agony, yet the darkness of past had blinded him from seeing the light of the present, momentarily. He nervously gasped for some air and moved out of the creaky chair, and looked at the clock behind him. It said 9.&lt;br /&gt;
“I like it at 9”, a voice whispered to him, freezing his nerves, before he realized it to be just a shockwave of his hallucination. He slowly stepped out to the corridor and left out a sigh, glad to have finally stepped into reality. The phone in his left pant pocket beeped.&lt;br /&gt;
MEETING WITH THE CHAIRMAN, flashed on the screen as a pre-set memo. Rajat hit his head with his hand. The damned dream had pushed him into a traumatic oblivion. He rushed to collect his files from his desk. Within the next few minutes, he was standing outside the executive cabin, waiting to be called in. He was supposed to give a presentation on the architectural planning of the company’s next shopping mall. Placement of shops, the outer designs, colour palettes and adherence to budget was all his work to do. He wanted it to go well, it had to. It could prove his golden chance to soar in appraisals. He was confident and the determination sparkled his eyes. He smiled in self-motivation and walked inside the cabin.&lt;br /&gt;
“Please come in, Mr. Rajat” a husky voice greeted him in. Strange it may sound, Rajat felt a peculiar familiarity with the voice. Seemingly, he had joined the dots but was reluctant to accept it. Dismissing his thoughts as bizarre, he walked in. the chair on the opposite side had been facing the wall. Despite the semi-darkness of the area, he could trace long beautiful fingers playing with what looked like a pendant. The figure nodded as Rajat greeted and begun with his presentations.
“So the color palette would be of white, cyan and yellow suiting the...”
“Red” interrupted the voice.&lt;br /&gt;
“Pardon me, ma’am?”, tingling an iota of restlessness in Rajat.&lt;br /&gt;
The figure moved out of the chair and started to walk towards Rajat.
Horrors of his dream started haunting him back. As the light fell on the figure’s face, Rajat could feel the dread, lately in his mind, coming to existence. As the earth beneath his feet started sliding away, he felt bouts of fear clutching the insides of his body. It was the face, the same face. She was the one he had dreamt of. The pendant was a white crystal. He had never so closely explored the dimensions of horror till now. His head felt dizzy and he wanted to faint right away to save himself from the apprehensions that scared him in the back of his mind.&lt;br /&gt;
The lady walked closer to him, smiling, and it seemed she was in total understanding with the multiple thoughts that were undeniably paralyzing. She bent for her lips to be close enough to his ear and uttered words that broke the last dint of courage Rajat had backed himself with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I want it red”.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 20:04:25 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://thewordsmiths.xyz/thriller/2016/07/02/fantasy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thewordsmiths.xyz/thriller/2016/07/02/fantasy.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thriller</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
