<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Wordsmiths</title>
    <description>Blog and Content Production Company
</description>
    <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rohanmishra97.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 18:36:41 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 18:36:41 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Feel</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Touch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;( &lt;i&gt;Fiction, 3 minute read&lt;/i&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She rushed on the subway. He followed her. Not saying a word to each other. What could they even say? Apparently there was nothing left to talk about. &quot;This couldn&#39;t be the end&quot;, both felt. Walking amidst the sunday flocks, he didn&#39;t lose sight of her even once. &lt;br /&gt;
He couldn&#39;t then, he can&#39;t now. She had always been the apple of his eye. Loving her more than anything else had been his first profession. Even before taking care of his ancestral shop in the suburbs. What salary for this profession, you may ask? Well, her love was much more than any remuneration he could even think of earning! &lt;br /&gt;
When she was sad, he would cry harder. When she was sick, the doctor treated him first. When she had a visit from little friend down south, he would stay by her side throughout. &lt;br /&gt;
People were sure their happiness was a decoy. But to be candid, it was more real than reality could be!&lt;br /&gt;
Defying all speculations of friends and foes, they had been together for ten lovely years. And hoped to continue till their last breath. Afterall, he hadn&#39;t even looked at another girl all these years. As for her, he was the best she could ever hope for. &lt;br /&gt;
But as they say, change is the only constant. Life had been harsh on them. Both of them. Why else would they live to see dreadful days which were yet to come?&lt;br /&gt;
Even before parting, both realized this. Dreadful days to come. Dreadful days to live through. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as she was about to exit the subway, she felt a tap on her shoulder. She skipped a beat. She was so elated at this gentle touch. This had indeed been his best touch till now! Never did she feel so overwhelmed. This touch gave her new hopes. Hopes which could save her from those days. Remember? Dreadful days. Hopes which could save the world from shattering into bits of useless pieces. &lt;br /&gt;
She turned with glee. Her eyes looking straight. Straight into the crowd. He didn&#39;t follow her no more. Nowhere to be seen, as far as her eyes could scan. Maybe it was his way to say goodbye. With a heavy heart and limbs numb, she stood looking through the crowd, hoping he would follow her again, sometime!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/fiction/2016/07/05/touch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/fiction/2016/07/05/touch.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Feel</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Feel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Poetry&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A strong case of feels they say,&lt;br /&gt;
Not at such a crucial time, I pray.&lt;br /&gt;
Thumping in the chest,&lt;br /&gt;
Pressure rising in veins&lt;br /&gt;
With every trough and crest&lt;br /&gt;
The heart starts to break the chains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel, my precious,&lt;br /&gt;
We weren’t meant to hold back.&lt;br /&gt;
Don’t pull the reins; be curious&lt;br /&gt;
Let yourself soar high.&lt;br /&gt;
Love. Cry. Fall. Or break.&lt;br /&gt;
Just don’t regret it at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is a journey,&lt;br /&gt;
Finished by all but enjoyed by the brave.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 20:04:25 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/poetry/2016/07/04/feels.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/poetry/2016/07/04/feels.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nostalgia</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Nostalgia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Poetry&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single moment, trapped in cellulose&lt;br /&gt;
Or a scent your nose never forgets. &lt;br /&gt;
A taste of your beloved or&lt;br /&gt;
Some view you shared with someone&lt;br /&gt;
Who is no longer there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memories seep through,&lt;br /&gt;
Emotions hit as pulses,&lt;br /&gt;
Then as waves&lt;br /&gt;
Washing you over the cliff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They find their way&lt;br /&gt;
Through your eyes&lt;br /&gt;
Drops turning to waterfall&lt;br /&gt;
You relive it as it once was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remembrance at times high or low&lt;br /&gt;
Is a terrible thing to bear.&lt;br /&gt;
Look forward; don’t cling on to past.&lt;br /&gt;
For that’s how you fare.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 20:04:25 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/poetry/2016/07/03/nostalgia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/poetry/2016/07/03/nostalgia.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Fantasy</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;The Fantasy :- &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Thriller, 7 minute read&lt;/i&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creaks of his dilapidated chair echoed in the baronial office work space. There was an eerie silence and the day was cognitively different from typical. Rajat waited for his computer to compile the Java and lazily turned at the digital clock on his grey desk. Two years, three months four day and the 13th hour of hard work, that would soon vanish unaccounted for. He sighed. Soon, sound of heavy footsteps marching right into the office corridor broke his parade of thoughts. Realizing the implication, Rajat hurried out to hail a convoy of corporate patrons, a corporate etiquette, probably. The group that trotted through the narrow corridor was led by a lady he had certainly never seen before. The lady was in a red pencil-skirt, topped by a satin white shirt tucked inside the skirt. She had let her brown cascade tied up in a high bun. There was an unusual charm that ran down her porcelain skin and perfectly beautified delicate features. She wore a white crystal pendant that hung loosely at the edge of her cleavage. As the swarm passed Rajat, she turned sharply to take a look at him. Her look was different and the smirk that momentarily changed the dimensions of her blood red lips was evil. Her eyes had a tinge of seduction and carried an aura of mystery, cold and deep. As they walked into the big conference room, the whispers and the sound of footsteps were gradually replaced by the pin-drop silence.&lt;br /&gt;
As our protagonist resumed his work, he found it hard to resist the thoughts of the anonymous lady he had just had an exchange of expressions with. She was wrapped in an unresolved mystery. It was not particularly scary yet had nothing to entice in a stable human mind but fear and anxiety. She had the essence that commanded attention and a disdain for interference resting in the backdrop. A combination of too many traits, with clarity of none. He had noticed her steps to be too light and fleeting. She didn’t wobble a step despite the sharply pointed heels she wore. There was a degree of perfection she carried that was far from generic. Someone among his colleagues had hinted her to be an ad-hoc for the ailing chairman, and thoughts of her being temporary lingered in his thoughts and saddened a part of his soul.&lt;br /&gt;
A knock interrupted Rajat’s engrossment, and he re-organised himself to save himself from any embarrassment, not very sure if his mentally seduced-self had not affected his physical one in sub consciousness.&lt;br /&gt;
“Arey, aaiye Pandey ji, come in.”, he smiled while gesturing the old clerk to come in, “Who is it now?”&lt;br /&gt;
“The new madam, Sirji, she wants to have a meeting with you”, the old clerk said while trying to flaunt his skills in English.&lt;br /&gt;
Momentarily, his heart stopped beating and the very next moment it bit so vigorously that he could feel his chest puffing in and out. A peculiar sense of ecstasy stretched his lips into a smile and sending him back to a hallucinated engrossment paired with too many questions. He managed to give a slight nod to the clerk. As the latter walked out of the cabin, Rajat turned himself towards the wall with the clock hanging on it.&lt;br /&gt;
Thirty minutes past ten, it said. Rajat smiled and briefed a small introduction, rehearsed it a few more times and started walking out of the cabin with a file in his hand, probably to look a tad more professional.&lt;br /&gt;
He sauntered to Madam’s cabin in order to veil his overwhelm and excitement. On reaching the cabin door, he could notice through the glass that the lady had her gaze fixed on the large antique clock on the textured wall, while her hands played with the white crystal pendant that had the prodigy of embracing her smooth skin. She had let her hair open and thick brown mass of hair fell over her shoulders. She looked obnoxious and intoxicated Rajat pushing him back to his world of secret thoughts.&lt;br /&gt;
“You may come in”, the lady said, slowly drifting her gaze towards Rajat. Her voice was melody. Was there anything about her not par perfection? Or was she a goddess in disguise? What if she actually was an angel without a halo? Umpteen nonsensical fantasies whirred his head as Rajat walked into the cabin, somewhat in trance. He tried looking here and there to save himself from doing anything embarrassing. The cabin had been renovated and it was majorly covered in red, seemingly thematic. A painting of a river of blood flowing, with desiccated bodies lying along the bay line hung behind the lady. It was eerie and awkward and crippled the romance that had lately been coveting Rajat’s senses. Bringing about what the lady commanded, fear. He turned his head to the left and was slightly surprised to see the big antique clock stuck at 9. Before he could raise a question, the only other voice in the room spoke up. “I like it at 9”. Suspense enhanced and fears were a replaced inhibition back in our hero’s mind.&lt;br /&gt;
“I hear you’re one of the most accomplished employees here. You have scored big time. I was curious to know more of you.”&lt;br /&gt;
Rajat managed a smile despite the most bizarre emotions ransacking his courage down the core.&lt;br /&gt;
“How do you like me?” the lady spoke in a manner that was too sharp to be ignored and too polite to be good. Her eyes narrowed as she pierced them into his, somewhat blurring his conscience.&lt;br /&gt;
“You’re beautiful”, Rajat said as he gulped a lump of self-apathy and shame down his throat.&lt;br /&gt;
She smiled and blushed and despite the bewildering fears, Rajat could not resist noticing how ravishing she looked with her cheeks tempting rosy shades of shyness. As he looked on, the lady got up and walked behind him, her steps too light and fleeting.&lt;br /&gt;
“Tell me more”, she whispered, bending upon her shoulders, and letting her long fingers play with the manly chest with a fragile heart underneath.&lt;br /&gt;
“I like the pendant that dangles down your neck”. Clueless of the silence that followed, Rajat apprehensively turned towards the lady, only to be left aghast.&lt;br /&gt;
Streams of black tears ran down the lady’s rosy cheeks.&lt;br /&gt;
“I wanted it red. I like red.” Rajat stared at the petrifying sight that hung over his shoulder, scarcely left with any of his senses. The mystery was unfolding and fears clutched every inch of his soul, making him too gullible to dare, too trapped to escape.&lt;br /&gt;
“Will you make it red?”, the lady spoke in deathly innocence, and before he could frame what had just happened, Rajat could see the charming visage turning beastly, with pale eyes and parched lips, and a growl before long canine teeth pulsated through his veins, draining every ounce of blood in his body. The world darkened around him, as he saw the white crystal turning red, blood red- his blood fulfilling the unfulfilled desires of a scarred soul, an uncanny barter at the cost of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A loud thump shook him off the nap he had slipped into. Rajat looked around and shrugged. His forehead shun with sweat and his face was pale, ironically as an expression of relief. A panoply of emotions gushed through his nerves. He felt like an escapist, a refugee who had liberated himself from the fetters of torture and agony, yet the darkness of past had blinded him from seeing the light of the present, momentarily. He nervously gasped for some air and moved out of the creaky chair, and looked at the clock behind him. It said 9.&lt;br /&gt;
“I like it at 9”, a voice whispered to him, freezing his nerves, before he realized it to be just a shockwave of his hallucination. He slowly stepped out to the corridor and left out a sigh, glad to have finally stepped into reality. The phone in his left pant pocket beeped.&lt;br /&gt;
MEETING WITH THE CHAIRMAN, flashed on the screen as a pre-set memo. Rajat hit his head with his hand. The damned dream had pushed him into a traumatic oblivion. He rushed to collect his files from his desk. Within the next few minutes, he was standing outside the executive cabin, waiting to be called in. He was supposed to give a presentation on the architectural planning of the company’s next shopping mall. Placement of shops, the outer designs, colour palettes and adherence to budget was all his work to do. He wanted it to go well, it had to. It could prove his golden chance to soar in appraisals. He was confident and the determination sparkled his eyes. He smiled in self-motivation and walked inside the cabin.&lt;br /&gt;
“Please come in, Mr. Rajat” a husky voice greeted him in. Strange it may sound, Rajat felt a peculiar familiarity with the voice. Seemingly, he had joined the dots but was reluctant to accept it. Dismissing his thoughts as bizarre, he walked in. the chair on the opposite side had been facing the wall. Despite the semi-darkness of the area, he could trace long beautiful fingers playing with what looked like a pendant. The figure nodded as Rajat greeted and begun with his presentations.
“So the color palette would be of white, cyan and yellow suiting the...”
“Red” interrupted the voice.&lt;br /&gt;
“Pardon me, ma’am?”, tingling an iota of restlessness in Rajat.&lt;br /&gt;
The figure moved out of the chair and started to walk towards Rajat.
Horrors of his dream started haunting him back. As the light fell on the figure’s face, Rajat could feel the dread, lately in his mind, coming to existence. As the earth beneath his feet started sliding away, he felt bouts of fear clutching the insides of his body. It was the face, the same face. She was the one he had dreamt of. The pendant was a white crystal. He had never so closely explored the dimensions of horror till now. His head felt dizzy and he wanted to faint right away to save himself from the apprehensions that scared him in the back of his mind.&lt;br /&gt;
The lady walked closer to him, smiling, and it seemed she was in total understanding with the multiple thoughts that were undeniably paralyzing. She bent for her lips to be close enough to his ear and uttered words that broke the last dint of courage Rajat had backed himself with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I want it red”.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 20:04:25 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/thriller/2016/07/02/fantasy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/thriller/2016/07/02/fantasy.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thriller</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Lonely Tyre</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;The Lonely Tyre &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Fiction, 2 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A perforated Tyre lies in the middle of a vast expansive desert. The only companions it had were a family of raccoons living inside, whose presence ensured that he wouldn’t feel lonely. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, he was annoyed that there was something inside it. He didn’t want them there. They would play, eat, sleep die inside it. Every time they died, he would feel a bit sad, and then one day, after the last of them left him, he was devastated. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s almost covered by layers of sand, it’s existence threatening to be futile. Afraid, it tries to move a bit. Being lifeless does not help. It concludes that it needs help. Trying to shout, he attempts to self inflate, but then the holes in him stop the inflation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It tries to remember the days when he was used in a car, a big blue classic. Everyone drooled when he would come. They’d touch him, marvel at it’s beauty and then go away. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then he couldn’t trust his memory, it was failing miserably. 
He remembers being stuck in a store room ever since he was born, slowly nibbled on by mice, left unused until one day intruders stole him. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They too realised that he was useless upon seeing the gaps in his soul that the mice made. 
Leaving him by the road on a misty desert, surrounded by cactii, they left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He realised that perhaps he had repressed these terrible memories because he thought life could not get worse than that. &lt;br /&gt;
But it did.&lt;br /&gt;
And now, he’s lonely and tired. He just wants to leave the world in peace. &lt;br /&gt;
But he can’t. &lt;br /&gt;
He isn’t alive in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 20:04:25 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/thriller/2016/07/01/tyre.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/thriller/2016/07/01/tyre.html</guid>
        
        <category>featured</category>
        
        
        <category>thriller</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>India Without British</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;INDIA WITHOUT BRITISH&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;( &lt;i&gt;Social Commentary, 3 minute read&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;British ruled India for almost 200 years that started as the East India Company (EIC) that came to the Indian subcontinent to trade. Robert Clive’s forces won the battle of Plassey in 1757 and hence established the EIC. Later, they established their rule over the subcontinent and hence became our overlords. Though they had to succumb to the Indian freedom struggle in 1947 and leave us in a confused state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since India became an independent nation, we’ve been cursing The Great Britain for enslaving us. But what if the British explorers had not discovered the peninsula? I would like to list the other aspect of the British rule, other than the ones our history teachers have taught us (mine was cool enough to tell us about this other aspect, though).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India used to be a collection of hundreds of independent states. British had a major role in unifying India, though not directly (it was Sardaar Patel who did that). But wasn’t it the British rule that led to the inculcation of the feeling of national pride and patriotism within the largely divided Indians. Had the British never come, we would’ve still been a collection of unnecessarily divided states fighting for existence in the modern world. The Mughal rule had fairly declined by then and hence Indians were under a constant threat of wars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They brought in many religious and social reforms which proved to be beneficial to a country that was struggling to adjust into the modern civilisation. Widow’s remarriage Act, abolition of Sati, abolition of untouchability were some of them. Moreover, they introduced us to the modern education system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They developed railways, postal systems and other means of communication. Here, I would want to add that though they this all to favour themselves and multiply their profits, all that they left behind is serving us now. Before 1947, India had around 50,000 kms of railway network whereas the Indian government added another 13,000 kms after independence which doesn’t even come close to the what British had laid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, we got access to better technology, better medical facilities, better hygiene habits, sanitation facilities and a modern outlook. Industrialisation, despite being responsible for the exploitation and unemployment of many Indians at that time, did something good for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no denying of the fact that they did everything in India to benefit their people and not the Indians. And, india could have achieved all this by itself as well but would the Indian subcontinent have been in the same shape as it is today? Were we even close to a nation before them? I agree that British rule had many more negatives than positives, but everything has two sides to it. Also, I am not a pro -British, at all. I too am a proud Indian citizen who dislikes the British rule as much as anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shreya Garg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 20:04:25 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/commentary/2016/07/01/india.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/commentary/2016/07/01/india.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>commentary</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Maya and the Pride</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Maya and the Pride&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;i&gt;Social Commentary, 4 minutes&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She looks into the broken piece of mirror, grinning hysterically at her jagged reflection, and contemplating as to where to make her cuts, so that it hurts less….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Then&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maya enjoyed the crisp morning breeze flowing in from the sea. Living in one of the most sought after houses in Juhu, she thought her life couldn’t get any better. She went over her mental check-list, crossing off items she had accomplished so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Have looks to die for– check”.&lt;br /&gt;
“Seduce a rich, successful guy– check”.&lt;br /&gt;
“Become a trophy wife– check”.&lt;br /&gt;
“Produce a son– check”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking over the last item, she was grateful that she had to get pregnant only once; pregnancy sure did mar a girl’s figure. But for all her vanity, she couldn’t be more proud of her one and only son, her pride and joy, her little Shlok, who wasn’t so little anymore. Winning the most sought after scholarship to Harvard Business School (yes, his father had no hand in it), he was off to follow his father’s footsteps and join in the family business, that of owning and managing the jewellery company. “All he needs is a suitable bride now” Maya thought. At 22, her son still didn’t have any romantic liaisons, not even an itty-bitty casual little fling. “Well”, she thought to herself, “Obviously, I raised him right, he’s a good little mama’s boy after all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finishing her cup of tea, she considered going over the speech that she had to deliver at the annual LGBTQ parade. Fighting relentlessly for homosexual rights, she knew these antics would put her and her family in media’s good graces. And it did work– the masses and elites alike tagged them as “People’s Champion”. Smiling benignly, she thanked lady luck for working so hard for her, and making things work out in her favour, always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Good morning Ma.” her son’s voice drew her out of her musings. Beaming at him, she replied, “A very good morning to you too! All packed and set for Boston? Flight’s tomorrow right?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yes Ma. Just some minute things are left, I’ll go over them in the evening. You seem unusually happy this morning. Pa’s coming back any time soon?”
“Haha, no, sadly. His meeting’s been delayed. Guess he’ll have to suffer the sweltering Delhi heat a bit more.”
“Ah well, I was hoping to meet him one last time before leaving. I had something to tell him”, he paused, before adding, “something to tell both of you actually.”
Hearing his slightly apprehensive tone, she tensed a bit. “What is it my love? You know you can tell me anything right? We always crossed every hurdle easily together, right?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yes, yes Ma, I know, hence I thought I’d say this before leaving, and get it off my chest. And well, it isn’t anything bad, just a slight reveal of sorts. Won’t be really shocking, I promise.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She waited for him to continue with bated breath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Ma, I’m gay, and already am in a long distance relationship with a guy named Sam. He’s partly the reason why I slogged after Harvard. Well, at least I won’t be in a long distance relationship anymore.” he added as an afterthought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How long..how long has it been, since you’ve..you’re..you’ve known?” Maya asks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“About since I guess when I was 13, and well I kissed a girl. Well actually, quite a few girls were kissed after that, and well, I really didn’t feel that spark that usually a normal hormonal boy would feel. It wasn’t until I kissed a guy in a game of truth-and-dare that my suspicions were confirmed. I just swing the other way, I guess.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That’s a heavy guess to take son.” Maya replied, a bit too coolly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, it’s just a phrase Ma. I mean, I’m sure I’m gay. In fact, I met Sam twice, in the course of last year. He came all the way from Boston, just for me. He’s great mum. I’ll make sure you meet him, when you visit me in Boston.”&lt;br /&gt;
“Okay, okay hold your horses now. Let me just digest the fact that you’re...well..”&lt;br /&gt;
“Gay, Ma. And I thought you wrote a whole speech for the pride parade the day after.”&lt;br /&gt;
“Well, you see son, it does come as a shock when you discover your one and only son doesn’t like girls!” she scoffed. Taking a deep breath, she added later, “It’s alright, sweetheart, the heart wants what it wants, right?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh Ma, I’m really sorry”, Shlok said pensively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s alright, honey, it will be alright” and got up and hugged him tight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Now&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She looks into the broken piece of mirror, grinning hysterically at her jagged reflection, and contemplating as to where to make her cuts, so that it hurts less.
“Why are you doing this Ma?” Shlok asked, quietly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Why do you think so son? ‘Course I can’t let you tarnish the family name now, can I? Do you realise how many losses I’ll be suffering when they discover the company’s only heir is ‘gay’? The society may seem like it has accepted your kind, but truthfully, they still look at you as a filthy plague”, his father puts in. Picking up another piece of the broken mirror, he moved over to the bed, where his son was bound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Maya, just stop thinking if this will hurt him or not. If you cannot do it, then just leave and get ready for the parade. You have a ‘speech’ to deliver”, Aakash says the last part with a smirk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh honey, you really brought this upon yourself.” Giving Shlok a last kiss, she left his room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while later, Aakash joins Maya on the foyer, where she was patiently waiting for him, so that they could depart for parade together. “Call the police”, he says, “tell them our son committed suicide. He slit his wrists.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right on cue, Maya releases a loud wail and dials 100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fin!&lt;/b&gt;
-&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/wordsmiths14&quot;&gt;Shreya Barua&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 16:19:30 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/27/maya-and-the-pride.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/27/maya-and-the-pride.html</guid>
        
        <category>pride</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        <category>thriller</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Faith</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Life, 2 minute read&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A busy market, she stands in the temple, peaceful, serene. Her eyes closed. While people around ask for material things, all she wants is to never lose faith
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Have faith&quot;; something her parents always tell her, her faith protects her when it&#39;s dark , it tells her to aim for peace and never hurt fellow beings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the street; he walks with increasing pace, pulling his handbag closer with every step,the clock is ticking faster every second, the handbag has to be placed at the right position in time. His forehead is filled with beads of perspiration, all the nervousness and fear is covered by the blanket of his faith.
Faith that he was born to do this, that heavens wait for his soul after the accomplishment of his mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market is filled to the brim; anything and everything is sold and bought.
Coming down the steps of the temple, her eye catches this man, walking with a brisk pace, a handbag hanging down his shoulder; just then his wallet drops out of his pocket, picking up the wallet she screams&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;**HEY**!&quot;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He turns around , a girl is screaming pointing at him, fear surmounts him, his legs freeze, she is running towards him, his limbs are no more in his control as he stands there as a statue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;*You dropped your wallet*&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looks down at his purse, then looks up at the girl smiling at him.
He takes the wallet pushing the handbag closer to his chest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;* Is something wrong?, you are sweating profusely *&quot; &lt;br /&gt;
&quot;*No, nothing.* &quot; He says turning around for his mission can&#39;t afford any delay.
&quot;*Have faith, all will be well*&quot;
He keeps walking as she speaks, she asks him to have faith,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HE HAS FAITH!
it drives all his fears away.
And soon his faith will win. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such different roles, such different meanings, still they use the same word &quot;faith&quot;.
He takes the bomb out, places his thumb on the red button, something stops him, the girl&#39;s smiling face floating in front of his eyes.
&quot;All will be well&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not for them,**FOR HIM!** &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heavens wait for his arrival.
A ball of fire engulfs the market . &lt;/p&gt;
- [Raghav Aggarwal] (http://www.facebook.com)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 02:03:10 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/24/faith.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/24/faith.html</guid>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>That Night</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;That Night&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(*Romance, 3 minute read *) &lt;br /&gt;
The sight of empty roads leading to her house was always exciting for him. The sight of cuckoo birds cuckooing in the middle of the night, the sounds of the night watchmen blowing their whistles, searching for fiends, thieves and what not, the sight of dogs sometimes sleeping peacefully, lying in the middle of the road, and the two of them, walking hand to hand, talking with each other.&lt;br /&gt;
Today was not one of those days. Rather, the last few months weren’t like this. She was walking next to him, unusually silent. His eyes weren’t searching for hers. The homeless people, frail and weak, sleeping in the sidewalk, the sound of the wind blowing with a hooting noise, rain drizzling slowly into the road, his eyes were busy looking at those things. He knew why, but didn’t feel like admitting it.&lt;br /&gt;
He thought of the reason this had to happen, where the things went wrong. He had thought a lot before, but could never pinpoint why.&lt;br /&gt; 
His eyes refused to twinkle when they saw her after a period of months, his heartbeat didn’t elevate, he just didn’t feel excited. &lt;br /&gt;
He stated the reason for this to be lack of sleep but he knew better. She was slowly realizing this.&lt;br /&gt;
Overridden with guilt, he had done nothing. The split was long overdue, but he didn’t know what he would say to her. &lt;br /&gt;
I can’t say I don’t like her anymore, he thought. She is so great, everything I need right now. But what can I do, I feel empty when I’m with her, I just don’t know why. &lt;br /&gt;
Catching her glancing at him, he could still see the sparkle in her eyes that he lacked. &lt;br /&gt;
What is happening, he thought. I don’t want to make this hard on her. What do I do? &lt;br /&gt;
She stopped walking, but he didn’t notice that, he walked on ahead. 
He heard her call the second time. Turning, back he saw her face was stone cold. &lt;br /&gt;
“Sid, I understand that you aren’t able to say this. If you can’t, then I will. I’m breaking up with you.”&lt;br /&gt;
Looking at her, he didn’t know what to say.&lt;br /&gt; 
“Aren’t you going to say something?” she asked.&lt;br /&gt; 
Her eyes turned pale. &lt;br /&gt;
Please don’t try to call me”, saying this she hurried forward, not looking back once.&lt;br /&gt;
He could hear her sobbing as she passed him. He didn’t stop her. &lt;br /&gt;
He felt liberated for that moment. The taste of freedom was too overwhelming. He felt happy, to his surprise. Feeling wrong about the way he felt, he turned around and ran, trying to not think of anything. &lt;br /&gt;
Still, the only thing that was in his mind was that he was free now.&lt;br /&gt;
But the guilt never went away.&lt;br /&gt;
– &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/wordsmiths14&quot;&gt;Santrupta Mishra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:03:10 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/24/the-night.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/24/the-night.html</guid>
        
        <category>romance</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cassette Nostalgia</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;The Cassette Nostalgia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Music, 2 minute read)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are days when you stay at home, doing nothing and suddenly your mother comes up and tortures you to get up from the couch and do some chores. So, one fine sunny morning I was forced by her to go and clean the attic.Being super lazy, I tried to do as little as possible and leave the room. Then something caught my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A box titled “Cassettes”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going through it I saw the collection of songs my brother had collected when he was a teenager. This brought forth a whirlpool of memories and the nostalgia was overpowering. So, I perched the cassette player on the desk and popped in a cassette. The songs were old and perhaps I’d even forgotten most of their lyrics, but there was some faint memory linked with the songs. It made me reminiscence the long drives we used to go with dad on our little and cozy Maruti and how we used to sing the songs along and aloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an iconic gesture that is related with the era of cassettes, when I used to stick a pencil in that coloured plastic case and rewiring a tape gone askewed. I also recall the intensity and focus with which my brother pressed the RECORD and PLAY button at the same time when he was making mixtapes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening to a tape is a different experience altogether. You can’t switch tracks as you wish, the glorious melody of a reel back or a fast forward, and the iconic low fidelity makes up for a unique and charismatic memory. There is a something unique and intangible about listening to a cassette tape with the songs from 90s. There is perhaps some form of romanticism associated with it, something that iPods and MP3 players can only hope to replicate, but in vain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My nostalgia and longing for the sounds and the mild distortions from the tape are really significant probably because this is a medium that stays intact. Probably, because I like feeling and touching the music. I can’t comprehend and completely experience the zeros and ones in the myriad of MP3 files on my phone. The artist’s nuances are lost in translation to me in the frequencies and algorithms of digitally mastering the songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening to cassette tapes sure was a trip down the memory lane for me. So if you are just another nostalgic kid of the 90s, I urge you to find a tape, sit down and listen to it. Trust me, it is worth it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
-&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/wordsmiths14&quot;&gt;Rohan Mishra&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:03:10 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/22/cassette-nostalgia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/22/cassette-nostalgia.html</guid>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        <category>nostalgia</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
