<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Wordsmiths</title>
    <description>Blog and Content Production Company
</description>
    <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rohanmishra97.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 21:25:58 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 21:25:58 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Faith</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;faith&quot;&gt;Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Life, 2 minute read&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A busy market, she stands in the temple, peaceful, serene. Her eyes closed. While people around ask for material things, all she wants is to never lose faith
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Have faith&quot;; something her parents always tell her, her faith protects her when it&#39;s dark , it tells her to aim for peace and never hurt fellow beings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the street; he walks with increasing pace, pulling his handbag closer with every step,the clock is ticking faster every second, the handbag has to be placed at the right position in time. His forehead is filled with beads of perspiration, all the nervousness and fear is covered by the blanket of his faith.
Faith that he was born to do this, that heavens wait for his soul after the accomplishment of his mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market is filled to the brim; anything and everything is sold and bought.
Coming down the steps of the temple, her eye catches this man, walking with a brisk pace, a handbag hanging down his shoulder; just then his wallet drops out of his pocket, picking up the wallet she screams&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;**HEY**!&quot;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He turns around , a girl is screaming pointing at him, fear surmounts him, his legs freeze, she is running towards him, his limbs are no more in his control as he stands there as a statue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;*You dropped your wallet*&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looks down at his purse, then looks up at the girl smiling at him.
He takes the wallet pushing the handbag closer to his chest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;* Is something wrong?, you are sweating profusely *&quot; &lt;br /&gt;
&quot;*No, nothing.* &quot; He says turning around for his mission can&#39;t afford any delay.
&quot;*Have faith, all will be well*&quot;
He keeps walking as she speaks, she asks him to have faith,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HE HAS FAITH!
it drives all his fears away.
And soon his faith will win. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such different roles, such different meanings, still they use the same word &quot;faith&quot;.
He takes the bomb out, places his thumb on the red button, something stops him, the girl&#39;s smiling face floating in front of his eyes.
&quot;All will be well&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not for them,**FOR HIM!** &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heavens wait for his arrival.
A ball of fire engulfs the market . &lt;/p&gt;
- [Raghav Aggarwal] (http://www.facebook.com)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 02:03:10 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/24/faith.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/24/faith.html</guid>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>That Night</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;that-night--&quot;&gt;That Night :-&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(*Romance, 3 minute read *) &lt;br /&gt;
The sight of empty roads leading to her house was always exciting for him. The sight of cuckoo birds cuckooing in the middle of the night, the sounds of the night watchmen blowing their whistles, searching for fiends, thieves and what not, the sight of dogs sometimes sleeping peacefully, lying in the middle of the road, and the two of them, walking hand to hand, talking with each other.&lt;br /&gt;
Today was not one of those days. Rather, the last few months weren’t like this. She was walking next to him, unusually silent. His eyes weren’t searching for hers. The homeless people, frail and weak, sleeping in the sidewalk, the sound of the wind blowing with a hooting noise, rain drizzling slowly into the road, his eyes were busy looking at those things. He knew why, but didn’t feel like admitting it.&lt;br /&gt;
He thought of the reason this had to happen, where the things went wrong. He had thought a lot before, but could never pinpoint why.&lt;br /&gt; 
His eyes refused to twinkle when they saw her after a period of months, his heartbeat didn’t elevate, he just didn’t feel excited. &lt;br /&gt;
He stated the reason for this to be lack of sleep but he knew better. She was slowly realizing this.&lt;br /&gt;
Overridden with guilt, he had done nothing. The split was long overdue, but he didn’t know what he would say to her. &lt;br /&gt;
I can’t say I don’t like her anymore, he thought. She is so great, everything I need right now. But what can I do, I feel empty when I’m with her, I just don’t know why. &lt;br /&gt;
Catching her glancing at him, he could still see the sparkle in her eyes that he lacked. &lt;br /&gt;
What is happening, he thought. I don’t want to make this hard on her. What do I do? &lt;br /&gt;
She stopped walking, but he didn’t notice that, he walked on ahead. 
He heard her call the second time. Turning, back he saw her face was stone cold. &lt;br /&gt;
“Sid, I understand that you aren’t able to say this. If you can’t, then I will. I’m breaking up with you.”&lt;br /&gt;
Looking at her, he didn’t know what to say.&lt;br /&gt; 
“Aren’t you going to say something?” she asked.&lt;br /&gt; 
Her eyes turned pale. &lt;br /&gt;
Please don’t try to call me”, saying this she hurried forward, not looking back once.&lt;br /&gt;
He could hear her sobbing as she passed him. He didn’t stop her. &lt;br /&gt;
He felt liberated for that moment. The taste of freedom was too overwhelming. He felt happy, to his surprise. Feeling wrong about the way he felt, he turned around and ran, trying to not think of anything. &lt;br /&gt;
Still, the only thing that was in his mind was that he was free now.&lt;br /&gt;
But the guilt never went away.&lt;br /&gt;
– &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/wordsmiths14&quot;&gt;Santrupta Mishra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:03:10 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/24/the-night.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/24/the-night.html</guid>
        
        <category>romance</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cassette Nostalgia</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-cassette-nostalgia&quot;&gt;The Cassette Nostalgia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Music, 2 minute read)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are days when you stay at home, doing nothing and suddenly your mother comes up and tortures you to get up from the couch and do some chores. So, one fine sunny morning I was forced by her to go and clean the attic.Being super lazy, I tried to do as little as possible and leave the room. Then something caught my attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A box titled “Cassettes”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going through it I saw the collection of songs my brother had collected when he was a teenager. This brought forth a whirlpool of memories and the nostalgia was overpowering. So, I perched the cassette player on the desk and popped in a cassette. The songs were old and perhaps I’d even forgotten most of their lyrics, but there was some faint memory linked with the songs. It made me reminiscence the long drives we used to go with dad on our little and cozy Maruti and how we used to sing the songs along and aloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an iconic gesture that is related with the era of cassettes, when I used to stick a pencil in that coloured plastic case and rewiring a tape gone askewed. I also recall the intensity and focus with which my brother pressed the RECORD and PLAY button at the same time when he was making mixtapes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening to a tape is a different experience altogether. You can’t switch tracks as you wish, the glorious melody of a reel back or a fast forward, and the iconic low fidelity makes up for a unique and charismatic memory. There is a something unique and intangible about listening to a cassette tape with the songs from 90s. There is perhaps some form of romanticism associated with it, something that iPods and MP3 players can only hope to replicate, but in vain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My nostalgia and longing for the sounds and the mild distortions from the tape are really significant probably because this is a medium that stays intact. Probably, because I like feeling and touching the music. I can’t comprehend and completely experience the zeros and ones in the myriad of MP3 files on my phone. The artist’s nuances are lost in translation to me in the frequencies and algorithms of digitally mastering the songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening to cassette tapes sure was a trip down the memory lane for me. So if you are just another nostalgic kid of the 90s, I urge you to find a tape, sit down and listen to it. Trust me, it is worth it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
-&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/wordsmiths14&quot;&gt;Rohan Mishra&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:03:10 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/22/cassette-nostalgia.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/22/cassette-nostalgia.html</guid>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        <category>nostalgia</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>89 Cuts Deep</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;cuts-deep-br&quot;&gt;89 Cuts Deep. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;( &lt;em&gt;Social Commentary - 3 minute read&lt;/em&gt; ) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*I* am sorry, but this is going to be yet another article on ‘Udta Punjab’ and how incredibly screwed up our ‘system’ is. I have thrown in some jokes on Pahlaj Nihalani as well for your liking! But first of all let’s go back in time where Kanti Shah ruled the single screens across the nation. The 90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 90s came liberalisation, a new form of Indian-ness, a radical change in the tone of movies and soaps that depicted how ‘free’ and ‘broad-minded’ we Indians are. And with that came a new vigour to conservatism, an effort to put a check to the endless and useless item songs and perverted scenes in movies. I thank God that happened. There were some good movies, some average but there were which some I can’t forget, and I surely don’t mean it in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come the new millennium and we have great movies and moreover, we have the Social Media. I, personally, think Facebook is like highschool, but everyone has a microphone to yell into. With every mindless trend there is, we are sure to chime in. Now, before I start ranting, let me get back to my love, movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CBFC, colloquially called ‘The Censor Board’, is a government established ‘independent’ agency whose purpose is to provide certification to movies and also check for anything that should offend anyone or send some wrong message across. That, is a big responsibility. Any idea that could harm the society or distract the masses should and must be checked. This is of utmost importance, given that we have the largest and perhaps the most impressionable youth in the world. However, the CBFC, the ‘Big Brother’ if you will has vested interests, which is no big surprise. It has often been alleged to involve in corruption to give improper ratings to some films and has garnered a really bad image for itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me state this clear and straight. I absolutely hate the fact that the board allowed thoroughly perverted movies like ‘Mastizaade’ , countless item songs about some two-syllabled dame, or the innuendos strewn all across movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Board may be broken. However, it shouldn’t be discarded as a whole. India plays host to a plethora of religious and social minorities, with said minorities battling both amongst themselves and the majority for better rights and privileges. All of this mostly leads to a very frail environment for cordial ties to develop. Complete freedom of speech might further add to the tension that breeds in the country. And we need censor board to regulate that. Freedom of speech can never be placed before peace as a priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need a censorship board, not to ban everything like they do in cousin Kim Jong Un’s land, but to hinder and provide a check to the unnecessary and the misconstrued which plan to make money off senseless debauchery. We need censorship, to initiate the dialogue to determine where to draw the line between being ‘broad-minded’ and being ‘amoral’.
Censors know that they can’t control the public cultural and media space. Although they cut this or that, my primary belief is that censorship, itself is a performative art, an assertion of authority and in a way, it capitalises on the controversy. Authority thrives on attention; and the CBFC sure does get a lot of attention. In this public culture of dilemma with all the media, the social platforms and countless other forms of communication, the Censorship Board is one player out of many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/wordsmiths14&quot;&gt;Rohan Mishra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 14:30:10 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/social/2016/06/20/cuts-deep.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/social/2016/06/20/cuts-deep.html</guid>
        
        <category>Social</category>
        
        <category>commentary</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>social</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Morning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Romance&lt;/em&gt; - 3 minute read )&lt;br /&gt;
The man could swear that he heard the train yawn as it pulled up on the station. The slumber seethed through every inch of the metal. It irritated the fuck out of him. The feeling was not unjustified. It was a bright, sunny morning, the first working day of the week. Causality was at play. The entire city seemed to be travelling together, some of them slumped in their seats, trying to catch a few more minutes of precious sleep, ‘got to wear that hangover out’; the ones standing up were either lustily looking for seats or had resigned to their fates and closed their eyes, ‘please lord, can’t afford to sleep on the job, the son of a bitch will fire me’. The stifling claustrophobia made him nauseous as he tried in vain to make some space for himself. Asphyxiation seemed imminent. For the next two hours, his body would be puppet to his fellow passenger’s desire and adjustments for space. He was fighting with his legs for some space when it hit him. His heart skipped a beat and then it skipped one more. The indistinct smell of perfume drifted lazily along the length of the train as the man tried desperately to recollect his senses. Memories flooded his head as it jerked up alert and like a pigeon started looking for the source of that undeniable scent.
She lived in his head even today. A breath of the fresh, mountain air.&lt;br /&gt;
  He tried to peer through the collage of limbs. &lt;br /&gt;
He could feel her body against him as they embraced. How far they had to hide for a single embrace. Was that her? He squinted.
He was in school again. They were not sitting together, but they looked at each other at the same time, she blinked at him and for the thousandth time, he was awestruck at her beauty, he blinked at her.&lt;br /&gt;
No, that was not her. Her hair were magical.&lt;br /&gt;
He was writing in his notebook when something knocked against his thigh. He knew what it was. Butterflies invaded his stomach. Ha, we called them flutterflies. The hand knocked against his thigh again and beckoned his. He slipped down his hand and they entwined their fingers together as the flutterflies ate his insides.
Where are you, where are you. He wished he had more eyes. WHERE ARE YOU.
He almost fell on the man in front of him as the train jerked to a stop. This one wasn’t a particularly busy station. A person was walking away from the train.
Those hair.. He could know those hair with his eyes closed. She was walking away. He was sorry. He almost shouted for forgiveness, trying to fight his way through to the open doors.&lt;br /&gt;
They slammed shut before he could reach them&lt;br /&gt;
. Fin.&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/wordsmiths14&quot;&gt;Harsh Pandey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 20:04:25 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/19/the-morning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/19/the-morning.html</guid>
        
        <category>romance</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Dad and Pink Floyd</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My dad and Pink Floyd&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
(&lt;em&gt;Music, 3 minutes&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;br /&gt;
It was the year of 1979. My dad, a teenager then, heard something that changed his life. From the transistor radio, he heard a guitar solo which spoke to him. The lyrics were subliminal. He couldn’t wait to know which song was this and what band made such a poignant track that conveyed so much, in such a simple form.
At the end of the song, the radio jockey muttered in his unmindfulness “This was Pink Floyd, next on track, ladies and gentlemen: Bob Dylan.”&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Hey mister tambourine man … * but he didn’t pay attention to that, he was already lost in thought.&lt;br /&gt;
*Pink Floyd.&lt;/em&gt;
He walked down to the nearest record store the other day and asked for Pink Floyd’s latest album. The owner handed him a vinyl record which was packaged with exquisite artwork. It was called, “&lt;strong&gt;The Animals&lt;/strong&gt;”. He biked back hurriedly, and listened to the album hoping to hear that solo. Although he couldn’t find the song he was searching for, he loved the album. The lyrical content, the imagery and the psychedelic effects it had!&lt;br /&gt;
There was no turning back, my dad was in love with Pink Floyd. For years to come, he collected posters of David Gilmour, impersonated Roger Waters while he remembered every nuance and every guitar riff of the songs.&lt;br /&gt;
Later that year, he found out the song he had been searching for, in the album “&lt;strong&gt;The Wall.&lt;/strong&gt;” The song was called, “Comfortably Numb”. He lapped up on the songs. He hums, “One of my turns” and “The Trial” till date. He read and scavenged for Pink Floyd. After nearly 8 years of pure fandom, he found a VHS recording of their live concert when he was in college. That was the first time he saw them perform!&lt;br /&gt;
Even now, I can assure you, the first Pink Floyd song you’ll hear will most likely is Comfortably Numb but chances are, you’ll listen to one song on Spotify, read up about them on Wikipedia and catch a concert on Youtube, then like it so much that you download their discography and then after 2 days, forget all about it after you find another “awesome band” and not feel connected to this one like my Dad and other kids of that generation did.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sure, you can find more music and movies than my dad could ever imagine! But then isn’t there some sweetness in scarcity? The sheer madness and absolute fandom is it’s own reward.&lt;br /&gt;
You can surely listen to a lot of music and store gazillion songs on your iPod but imagine the joy of standing in queue waiting to get your hands on the new record by Pink Floyd..&lt;br /&gt;
That, is special.&lt;br /&gt;
-&lt;strong&gt;Santrupta and Rohan Mishra&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 20:04:25 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/19/pink-floyd.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/fiction/2016/06/19/pink-floyd.html</guid>
        
        <category>romance</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Bait</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bait&quot;&gt;The Bait&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Life, 2 minute read&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does this happen sometimes? That even when you do not want to go inside the trap, you most willingly do. You enjoy it. You know it is harmful in the long run, yet you enjoy it. It eats you from within slowly and gradually. Why do you still not force yourself to stop at the threshold when you already know of the consequences? Why do you so easily give in to the temptation? Why is that you waste your life chasing the bait? What will you gain out of it? In the end its worthless. You are the only thing you have in this world. No one else. Yet you do this injustice to yourself. You say that someone means more than you do to your own self
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repeatedly chanting the same thing becomes a part of your being. You can&#39;t imagine your life without the bait. Yes, you are trapped. Scared? Oh no. Its just the starting. This is what you longed for. And the worst part will be that others around you will also be behind the bait, sometimes your own bait. In the process of chasing it, you are bound to feel behind others. You are bound to feel as if you don&#39;t deserve the bait. Maybe it is more expensive than you can afford. Maybe it is more spicy than your taste buds can handle. Very late in life do you realise that it isn&#39;t yours. Not in your destiny. In this process you lose yourself. You are lost in this world of unknowns. You feel broken. You cry. You feel terrible. Life is miserable. Life is not kind always. Life can take strange turns you wouldn&#39;t want it to take. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you are silly, my friend. You thought life was a cakewalk. By the end of it all, you would have met new people, ate different dishes, been to different places, but the one thing that will not leave your mind even when u die is that bait. That bait could have been your life. But hell, it didn&#39;t turn out that way. All you can do is die now. Or maybe die later. How does that make a difference anyway. After all you are dying from within ever since. And almost dead now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Note to the reader*: Love yourself. And above loving, respect yourself. Respect your own self-respect. No &#39;your-self-respect&#39; intruder is to be allowed to stay in your life. Know your worth. It is amazing to love and even better to be loved. But if that *bait* is no good for your development as a individual, and even worse if you are losing yourself in the process, then what is the whole point? Was losing yourself the initial goal? You wanted to come across others as a weak individual? If the answer is even a hesitant, slight &quot;NO&quot;, i guess you are in the wrong place. Do yourself a favour by quitting before it&#39;s too late!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/wordsmiths14&quot;&gt;Gursifath Bhasin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 20:04:25 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/philosophy/2016/06/17/the-bait.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rohanmishra97.github.io/blog/philosophy/2016/06/17/the-bait.html</guid>
        
        <category>featured</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>philosophy</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
